<TEXT>
Figure 1. Citation frequency of open access (OA) and subscription access (Sub) articles 36 mo after publication. Interpretive notes: boxes represent the interquartile range (25th to 75th percentile) and contain the median value (horizontal line) and average value (horizontal dash). Whis- kers extend 1.5(cid:6) the length of the interquartile range. Category notes: medical includes 5 journals published by the American Heart Association plus Neuro-Oncology, published by Duke University Press. Life sciences includes The FASEB Journal, Genetics, and 11 journals published by the American Physiological Society. Multidisciplinary sciences includes Sci- ence Magazine. Social sciences includes 10 journals published by Sage Publications. Humanities includes 6 journals pub- lished by Duke University Press. See Table 1 for treatment allocation.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
DISCUSSION
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Free access to scientific articles increases readership (as measured by article downloads) and reaches a broader audience (as measured by unique IP addresses) but has no effect on article citations within the first 3 yr after publication. These results are consistent with earlier trial reports on the physiology literature (14, 15) and suggest that these claims are generalizable across the scientific, social sciences, and humanities literatures.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
The increase in full-text downloads for open access articles during their first year after publication suggests that the primary benefit to the nonsubscriber commu- nity is in browsing, as opposed to printing or saving, which would have been indicated by a commensurate increase in PDF downloads. The decrease in abstract views suggests a reader preference for the full docu- ment when available.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
Prior studies comparing the citation impact of open access articles to subscription access articles are based on unobtrusive observational methods and may suffer from the failure to adequately control for confounding variables (8, 13). While some studies attempt to control statistically for differences in article characteristics,
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
such as article type, discipline, and funding source, (9), for example, none were able to control for abstract qualities such as relevance, novelty, and importance to a field of study, variables that are unobservable to the researcher. In addition, an author’s willingness and ability to pay open access publishing fees, some amounting to several thousands of dollars, may make simple performance comparisons with subscription- access articles highly problematic (12). By randomly altering access status in an experimental trial, we are able to isolate and measure the effects of access on readership and citations independently of other con- founding variables.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Measuring knowledge transfer
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Article downloads and citations measure two different dimensions of scientific knowledge transfer. The first measures general interest in a particular new piece of knowledge; the second measures the incorporation of that knowledge into a new document. Most article downloads take place within the first few months after publication (17, 18), suggesting that the primary func- tion of an article is to keep researchers abreast on the latest findings within a field and secondly to serve as a source document for future citation. Article downloads retrieved shortly after publication have been shown to predict future citations, although their strength of prediction is relatively low (17, 19, 20). A citation, on the other hand, measures a different set of intentions from a much smaller group of partic- ipants. To generate new scientific knowledge, in most cases, one must have access to equipment, materials and facilities, technicians, and the infrastructure neces- sary to support and coordinate them all (21). Authors must be able to analyze their results, capable of pre- senting their findings, and able to communicate them clearly and coherently. Once submitted, scientific man- uscripts must make it through peer-review and be published in an indexed journal in order to be visible
</TEXT>
<CAPTION>
TABLE 3. Likelihood of being cited within first year
</CAPTION>
<TABLE>
Articles cited Odds  ratio
Category                (%)         (OA/sub)     (cid:7)2 P (cid:4) (cid:7)2
All journals            74.1          0.96      0.11     0.74
Medical                 85.2          1.21      0.35     0.55
Life sciences           74.5          0.87      1.10     0.29
Multidisciplinary
  sciences              97.5          1.26      0.05     0.83
Social sciences         35.6          1.36      1.19     0.28
Humanities              10.0          0.43      0.96     0.33
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
Logistic regression controls for individual journal and journal categoryeffects.OA,openaccess;sub,subscription.Medicalincludes 5 journals published by the American Heart Association plus Neuro- Oncology, published by Duke University Press. Life sciences includes The FASEB Journal, Genetics, and 11 journals published by the Ameri- can Physiological Society. Multidisciplinary sciences includes Science Magazine. Social sciences includes 10 journals published by Sage Publications. Humanities includes 6 journals published by Duke University Press. See Table 1 for treatment allocation.
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
2132    Vol. 25   July 2011
</UNSPECIFIED>
<UNSPECIFIED>
The FASEB   Journal (cid:1) www.fasebj.org
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
DAVIS
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Downloaded   from www.fasebj.org  by (111.88.177.170) on April 13, 2020. The FASEB  Journal Vol. ${article.issue.getVolume()}, No. ${article.issue.getIssueNumber()}, pp. 2129-2134.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
