<TITLE>
EMPLOYMENT ELIGIBILITY VERIFICATION
</TITLE>
<TEXT>
National University is pleased to offer a Tuition Scholarship to university partners and their employees, in addition to spouses and dependents if included in the partnership agreement. To become eligible, you must be admitted in accordance with National University’s existing admission requirements and processes for undergraduate- and graduate-level programs and/or coursework, and be currently employed by a university partner.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
If you are enrolled into one of the approved spouse/dependent partnership programs, you must provide verification that your spouse or parent is a current employee (sponsor employee) of the contracted university partner by providing a letter of verification from your sponsored employee. Students who enroll must provide proof of employment/eligibility annually. In order to remain eligible, you must be and remain affiliated with the organization that has an agreement with the university as stated in the contracted terms. Discounts and eligibility vary by organization, and not all degree programs and certificates are eligible for a discount/scholarship. Please also note that program availability will vary by state.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
SECTION I: EMPLOYEE’S INFORMATION AND ATTESTATION
</SECTION_HEADER>
<SECTION_HEADER>
I attest that I am (select one option):
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
Student’s Name:                                                        Student ID#:
Business Telephone:                                                    Work  Email:
Company:                                                               Job Title:
Company   Address:
Company   Contact (Supervisor, HR Professional):
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
SECTION II: VERIFICATION DOCUMENT
</SECTION_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
- A dependent  is defined as a biological child, stepchild, adopted, and/or foster child
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
<TEXT>
I authorize release of the employment information above as requested and understand that National University/National University System reserves the right to request additional documentation above and beyond what is listed in this form, in order to verify eligibility at any time.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
AUTHORIZATION TO RELEASE STUDENT RECORDS
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
This section of the form is utilized to give third party organizations permission to verbally speak and electronically receive academic and financial student information from National University (NU), for the purpose of providing, maintaining, and/or administering Tuition Scholarships and other corporate benefits. This information includes personal information such as student name, Student ID, school status, document status and Organization name, financial information related to billing, financial aid, account balances, account statements, payments due and benefits earned, and academic information including but not limited to grades, credits attempted/earned, GPA, unsuccessful grades, program, start date, course names, and period of attendance.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
Per The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), NU will only disclose confidential information from the student’s education record to third parties if NU has written consent from the student. By signing below, you are providing written consent for NU stakeholders to verbally and in writing communicate with your related third-party organization(s).
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Printed Employee/Student Name                                                Date:
Signature of Employee/Student                                                Date:
</FORM>
<UNSPECIFIED>
[ ] Tuition Assistance  Voucher  or Letter  of Credit from university partner; or
Signature of Employee/Student                                                 Date:
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
