<SECTION_HEADER>
Student Information
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
Name                                                                                            Class Year              UG       LAW
          Last                       First                    Middle
Cell Phone:         -          -                      Date  of Birth:      /       /                   Male     Female      Other
                                                                      M       D        Y
</FORM>
<TEXT>
Washington and Lee University requires all full-time students to carry health insurance. You have the option of purchasing a Student Health Insurance Plan offered to all full-time students. All international students will be enrolled in the Student Health Insurance Plan offered through the University. You may review the policy brochure and apply for coverage on-line at http://www.firststudent.com - select W&L from the list of schools and click on “Review Brochure” or “Enroll Now.” Eligible dependents, including domestic partners, may enroll in this insurance plan once the student is enrolled.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
I plan to ENROLL in the Student Health Insurance Plan offered to all full-time students.
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
If you wish to waive the Student Health Insurance Plan offered through the University you must supply information about your current health insurance plan: policyholder's name and contact information, ID and policy number, name and address of the insurance carrier (the insurance plan MUST have a U.S. address), the phone number for claims service; and answer the questions below about your plan.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Policyholder   Information
  Name                                                             Name
  Address                                                          Address
  City                                                             City
  State           ZIP                                              State            ZIP
  Phone  (       )         -                                       Phone  (       )          -
Insurance   Information                                       Please  attach  a copy  of all insurance   cards  (front & back)
 Policyholder Name                                                 ID#                              Group  #
 Insurance  Company’s  Name                                                                    Phone  #        -       -
 Address                                                City                            State            ZIP            -
 Is this a state Medicaid plan?   No       Yes   If yes, which state?
 Is this an HMO plan?      No       Yes  If yes, please request guest membership in Virginia under your plan.
</FORM>
<TEXT>
• I hereby authorize and request Washington and Lee University to submit necessary information, including information from my health record, to my health insurance plan for the purpose of filing and processing claims for services provided at the Student Health Center.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
(Rev. 2/20)
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
Student Signature (if age 18 or older)
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                                                                                      This form  is to be submitted at
   I plan to WAIVE    the Student   Health  Insurance   Plan  as I am covered   by  the following  health  insurance   plan:
• I further authorize payment  for all such covered services  and  health insurance  benefits to be made   directly to Washington  and  Lee
University.
collect such payment   from  me  by placing a charge  on my  University  account, for which  I am financially responsible.
• I understand  that if I want to ensure that Explanation of Benefits statements  are sent  directly to me, the insured (rather than to the
policyholder), I am responsible  for contacting my  health insurance   plan to make  that request.
                                                                             Date
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
