<TITLE>
MONTHLY AUTO DRAFT APPLICATION/ AUTHORIZATION
</TITLE>
<SECTION_HEADER>
1. Complete and sign this application
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
(Optional) I would like an additional $             debited  each month  and applied to my principal balance.
(Optional) I would like an additional $             debited each  month  and applied to my escrow  account.
</FORM>
<TEXT>
By submitting this application, you authorize Trustmark National Bank (Trustmark) to debit the account specified above for the amount of your scheduled monthly mortgage payment due plus any additional principal and/or escrow that you may select. In the event that the monthly payment changes due to increases or decreases in the escrow account or interest rate (if applicable), Trustmark will notify you in writing before the change occurs and will automatically adjust the monthly debit amount for you. It is your responsibility to notify Trustmark of any changes to the above account/bank information at least 15 days prior to next draft date. This draft authorization will continue for the life of the loan or until I/We revoke this authorization in writing at least 15 days prior to draft date.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
3. Send the completed form to:
</SECTION_HEADER>
<SECTION_HEADER>
4. Receive Confirmation
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Upon successful enrollment in the ACH program, you will receive a written confirmation letter via mail or email. The confirmation letter will identify the date of the first scheduled ACH draft payment. Trustmark will not be able to process the application if the loan is not current. Please continue to make the normal mortgage payments until you receive your written confirmation letter stating your effective date of your ACH draft.
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
            Draft my payment on the due date
            Draft my payment on the          day of the month. You can select 1-15.
       Loan Number:                                            Bank  Name:
       Borrower Name:                                          Routing Number:
       Borrower Name:                                          Account  Number:
       Property Address:                                       Account  Type:        Checking     Savings
 Signature(s):
 Date:
**All bank account holders and  note holders must sign this application.
2.   Attach a voided  check or savings account  deposit slip from your bank
                                        Routing Number           Account Number
                          Automatic  Draft Department, Mortgage Loan Administration
                          201 Country Place Parkway, Suite B
                          Pearl, MS 39208
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
