<SECTION_HEADER>
Is OMM the same as chiropractic?
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
DOs are perhaps most commonly confused with DCs, or Doctors of Chiropractic. While there is some overlap between the two types of practitioners, they represent dis- tinct professions and separate schools of thought. Chi- ropractic was first enunciated in 1895 by Daniel David Palmer, who observed that displacement of vertebrae could affect neurotransmission, thus manifesting as dis- ease. Palmer was a magnetic healer, but unlike A.T. Still, he did not have a medical background. While the chiro- practic philosophy is historically focused on the nervous system, the original notion of osteopathic medicine was the need to restore blood flow, in particular, via manipula- tion of the neuromusculoskeletal system.6 The differences in education and training between the two professions are apparent. A table comparing the background of DOs, MDs, and DCs is provided below.16 It is important to note that DOs who go on to specialize in neuromusculoskeltal
</TEXT>
<TABLE>
Degree
Category                   DO              MD               DC
                     4-year           4-year          90 hours  of
                     degree           degree          college credit
Undergraduate                                         (Some
training
                                                      require a
                                                      degree)
                     4-year           4-year          4-year
Graduate  train-     Osteopathic      Medical De-     Chiropractic
ing                  Medical          gree (MD)       Degree  (DC)
                     Degree  (DO)
                     • 1-year         • 1-year        None
                     Internship       Internship
Postgraduate         • 2-8 years      • 2-8 years
training             of Residency     of Residency
                     (varies with     (varies with
                     specialty)       specialty)
                     Fully            Fully           Licensed
                     Licensed  to     Licensed to     to practice
                     practice the     practice the    chiropractic
                     complete         complete        manipulation.
Licensure/Scope      spectrum         spectrum
of Practice          of medical       of medical
                     and surgical     and surgical
                     specialties      specialties
                     in the United    in the United
                     States.          States.
Can  Prescribe       Yes              Yes             No
Medications
                     Over 200         None            Over  500
                     hours years                      hours.
Manual               1 and 2;
Medicine             over 100
Training             hours years
                     3 and 4.
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
medicine (NMM) and OMM obtain many more hundreds of hours of manual medicine training in a wider variety of clinical settings than DCs and other DOs. This section was meant to give you a better sense of what “osteopathic manipulative medicine” entails, and hopefully it answered most of your questions regarding OMM. The effectiveness of OMM remains a topic of ongoing debate and research despite past and current efforts to lay these arguments to rest. Whether an osteo- pathic physician uses OMM in his or her practice is based entirely on preference. With that said, it is an important core discipline and primary distinction of the osteopathic profession.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Additional Resources
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Cramer D, Miulli DE, Valcore JC, et al. Effect of pedal pump and thoracic pump techniques on intracranial pres- sure in patients with traumatic brain injuries. J Am Osteo- pathic Assoc. 2010; 110(4): 232-238. Crow WT, Gorodinsky L. Does osteopathic manipula- tive treatment (OMT) improve outcomes in patients who develop postoperative ileus: A retrospective chart review. International Journal of Osteopathic Medicine. 2009; 12(1):32-37.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
21
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
A Brief Guide to Osteopathic Medicine - For Students, By Students
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
Back to Table of Contents
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Chapter   3: Breaking   Down    Osteopathic    Manipulative    Medicine
                                       Cruser  DA, Maurer  D, Hensel K, et al. A randomized,
                                       controlled trial of osteopathic manipulative treatment
                                       for acute low back pain in active duty military personnel.
                                       J Man  Manip  Ther. 2012; 20(1):5-15. doi:10.1179/2042618
                                       611Y.0000000016.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
