<FORM>
Term               Definition
Standard           This is a generally accepted patient-care strategy that reflects a high degree of clinical certainty. The term standard generally
                   implies the use of Level 1 Evidence,  which  directly addresses the clinical issue, or overwhelming Level  2 Evidence.
Guideline          This is a patient-care strategy that reflects a moderate degree of clinical certainty. The term guideline  implies the use of
                   Level 2 Evidence  or a consensus  of Level 3 Evidence.
Option             This is a patient-care strategy that reflects uncertain clinical use. The term option implies insufficient, inconclusive, or con-
                   flicting evidence or conflicting expert opinion.
</FORM>
<TEXT>
ing sleep, or waking up too early, or sleep that is chronically nonrestorative or poor in quality. B. The above sleep difficulty occurs despite adequate opportunity and circumstances for sleep. C. At least one of the following forms of daytime impairment re- lated to the nighttime sleep difficulty is reported by the patient: 1. Fatigue or malaise; 2. Attention, concentration, or memory impairment; 3. Social or vocational dysfunction or poor school performance; 4. Mood disturbance or irritability; 5. Daytime sleepiness; 6. Motivation, energy, or initiative reduction; 7. Proneness for errors/accidents at work or while driving; 8. Tension, headaches, or gastrointestinal symptoms in re- sponse to sleep loss; and 9. Concerns or worries about sleep.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
veys, and frequent teleconference discussions, the expert panel identified consensus areas and recommendations for those areas not covered by AASM practice parameters. Recommendations were generated by panel members and discussed by all. To min- imize individual expert bias, the group anonymously voted and rated consensus recommendations from 1: strongly disagree to 9: strongly agree. Consensus was defined when all experts rated a recommendation 8 or 9. If consensus was not evident after the first vote, the consensus recommendations were discussed again, amended as appropriate, and a second anonymous vote was conducted. If consensus was not evident after the second vote, the process was repeated until consensus was attained to include or exclude a recommendation.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
AASM practice parameter papers are based on evidence- based review and grading of literature, often addressing a spe- cific issue or topic. Clinical guidelines provide clinicians with a working overview for disease or disorder evaluation and man- agement. These guidelines include practice parameter papers and also include areas with limited evidence in order to provide a comprehensive practice guideline. Both practice parameters and clinical guidelines define principles of practice that should meet the needs of most patients. They should not, however, be considered exhaustive, inclusive of all available methods of care, or exclusive of other methods of care reasonably expected to obtain the same results. The ultimate judgment regarding appropriateness of any specific therapy must be made by the clinician and patient in light of the individual circumstances presented by the patient, available diagnostic tools, accessible
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
treatment options, resources available, and other relevant fac- tors. The AASM expects this clinical guideline to have an im- pact on professional behavior and patient outcomes. It reflects the state of knowledge at the time of publication and will be reviewed, updated, and revised as new information becomes available.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
“Insomnia” has been used in different contexts to refer to either a symptom or a specific disorder. In this guideline, an insomnia disorder is defined as a subjective report of difficulty with sleep initiation, duration, consolidation, or quality that oc- curs despite adequate opportunity for sleep, and that result in some form of daytime impairment (Table 2). Except where otherwise noted, the word “insomnia” refers to an insomnia disorder in this guideline. Insomnia disorders have been categorized in various ways in different sleep disorder classification systems. The International Classification of Sleep Disorders, 2nd Edition (ICSD-2) is used as the basis for insomnia classification in this guideline. The ICSD-2 identifies insomnia as one of eight major categories of sleep disorders and, within this group, lists twelve specific in- somnia disorders (Table 3).
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
ICSD-2 delineates both general diagnostic criteria that apply to all insomnia disorders, as well as more specific criteria for each diagnosis. Insomnia complaints may also occur in asso- ciation with comorbid disorders or other sleep disorder catego- ries, such as sleep related breathing disorders, circadian rhythm sleep disorders, and sleep related movement disorders.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
Insomnia occurs in individuals of all ages and races, and has been observed across all cultures and countries.8,9 The actual prevalence of insomnia varies according to the stringency of the definition used. Insomnia symptoms occur in approximately 33% to 50% of the adult population; insomnia symptoms with dis- tress or impairment (i.e., general insomnia disorder) in 10% to 15%; and specific insomnia disorders in 5% to 10%.10 Consis- tent risk factors for insomnia include increasing age, female sex, comorbid (medical, psychiatric, sleep, and substance use) disor- ders, shift work, and possibly unemployment and lower socio- economic status. Patients with comorbid medical and psychiatric conditions are at particularly increased risk, with psychiatric and chronic pain disorders having insomnia rates as high as 50% to 75%.11-13 The risk relationship between insomnia and psychiatric disorders appears to be bidirectional; several studies have also
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
Journal of Clinical Sleep Medicine, Vol. 4, No. 5, 2008
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
490
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
S Schutte-Rodin, L Broch, D Buysse et al
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
  Table  1—AASM     Levels of Recommendations
  A. A A complaint complaint of of diffi difficulty culty initiating initiating sleep, sleep, diffi difficulty culty maintain- maintain-
                                                                                     INSOMNIA    DEFINITIONS    AND  EpIDEMIOlOGY
                                                                           Insomnia   Definitions
Use  of practice parameters   and  Clinical Guidelines                     Epidemiology
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
