<TEXT>
explaining this behaviour. Firstly, as indicated by a widely-cited study by a global consulting firm, increasing price would generate larger improvement in profit than other levers of profit (Fig. 3.7, p.31) (150). This may have influenced repeated price increases noted in the market for cancer medicines (147,151) and indeed, markets for patented and generic medicines in other therapeutic areas (152–154). Secondly, as there are many factors influencing demand of medicines other than price (50), it would be sensible for companies focused solely on maximizing profits to focus on price because as it has been said “price is certainty and volume is a bet”.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
1% increase  in
  profit levers:                        Improvement    in operating  profit
          Price                                                   +11.10%
Variable  cost
      Volume               +3.30%
    Fixed cost       +2.30%
</FORM>
<TITLE>
KEY POINTS
</TITLE>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
31
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Fig. 3.7: Comparison   of factors  of profit
▪   Market   concentration:   The market  structure of cancer medicines  is characterized by imperfect
    competition,  with evidence of individual companies   holding monopoly   over  specific cancer therapeutic
    areas. Companies   with market  dominance   are called price makers  because  they are able to set higher
    prices while maintaining  market share.
▪   Sources   of market  dominance:    (1) Protection of intellectual property allows companies to prevent
    generic/biosimilar competition  and  to employ  various strategies to preserve their market position; (2)
    lack of clinical substitutes occurs because of the differences in disease characteristics, therapeutic and
    safety profile, and standard evidence-based   treatment  protocols; (3) presence of “differentiated
    oligopoly” occurs, where  companies   attempt  to differentiate similar products; and (4) entry barriers
    prevent  other companies   from entering  the market due  to factors such as regulatory requirements,
    manufacturing   requirements,  patent disputes, and demand-side    factors (interchangeability criteria,
    perceived  inferiority).
▪   Monopolies    are inefficient because  monopolists   would  overcharge,  under-produce   and  produce  at
    higher costs than  in a competitive market, as evident in the cancer medicine  market.
▪   Companies    focus  on  price because  increasing price may  generate  larger improvement   in profit than
    other levers, and uptake  of cancer medicines  is uncertain because  of other non-price-related barriers to
    access.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
