<TEXT>
6. Identify the efflorescence. Knowing the composition of efflorescing salts is sometimes of use. Table 1, taken from Brownell’s report lists the most probable sources of efflorescing salts. Commercial testing laboratories can use X-ray diffraction, petrographic analysis or chemical analysis can, in some instances, determine both the type of salts present and their relative quantity. 7. Consider miscellaneous sources of water when all obvious sources have been eliminated. Some of these sources are: condensation within the wall, poorly directed landscape sprinklers, leaky pipes, faulty drains and condensation on heating or plumbing pipes. If necessary, condensation analysis methods are described in Technical Note 47.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
When the mechanisms causing the efflorescing salts to appear have been established and the sources of salts or moisture are identified (usually the latter), suitable corrections must be addressed. Solutions to efflorescence prob- lems usually involve reducing water penetration into the masonry and removing the efflorescence from the wall. Recommendations for the correction of water penetration in masonry walls are contained in Technical Note 46.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Removal of Efflorescence
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
It is usually not advisable to wash efflores- cence off of the brickwork except in warm, dry weather, since this results in the availability of considerably more moisture which may bring more salts to the surface. Many efflorescing salts can be removed by dry brushing. For recommendations concerning removing efflorescence and other stains on masonry walls, see Technical Note 20. Special care should be exercised in cleaning new masonry, since improper procedures and errors can contribute to or cause efflorescence or stains.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Coatings
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TABLE>
Principal Efflorescing   Salt           Most  Probable   Source
Calcium sulfate            CaSO  4●2H 2O       Brick
Sodium  sulfate            Na 2SO 4●10H 2O     Cement-brick  reactions
Potassium  sulfate         K 2SO 4             Cement-brick  reactions
Calcium carbonate          CaCO                Mortar    concrete
                                 3                    or
                                               backing
Sodium  carbonate          Na 2CO              Mortar
                                  3
Potassium  carbonate       K 2CO 3             Mortar
Potassium  chloride        KCl                 Acid Cleaning
Sodium  chloride           NaCl                Sea Water
Vanadyl  sulfate           VOSO                Brick
                                 4
Vanadyl  chloride          VOCl                Acid
                                2                   Cleaning
Manganese   oxide          Mn 3O               Brick
                                4
Iron oxide                 Fe 2O 3 or          Iron in contact or brick
                           Fe(OH) 3            with "black core" or
                                               "black heart"
Calcium hydroxide          Ca(OH) 2            Cement
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
Clear water repellents, silicone and acrylic coatings are among the solutions often sug- gested for preventing efflorescence. A coating may prevent efflorescence from recurring by reducing the amount of water absorbed by an exposed masonry surface. However, applying a coating to brickwork that has a tendency to effloresce, without stopping the mechanisms causing that efflorescence, may lead to deg- radation of the masonry. Further, applying a coating that inhibits evaporation of water from the masonry may also lead to degradation.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
As water and dissolved salts within masonry travel toward a coated exterior surface, they may be stopped at the inner margin of the coating (usually 1/ 8 to 1/ 4 in. [3 to 6 mm] below the surface). At this point, the water will evapo- rate, passing through the treated area as vapor and soluble salts in the water will be deposited within the mason- ry. Known as cryptoflorescnece or subflorescence, salts that crystallize within masonry can develop tremendous pressures which may result in brick spalling. For this reason, coatings are not recommended as the sole treatment for efflorescence problems.
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
www.gobrick.com       | Brick Industry  Association    | TN 23A   | Efflorescence     - Causes     and  Prevention     | Page   8 of 9
</UNSPECIFIED>
<UNSPECIFIED>
            TABLE   1
Common   Sources  of Efflorescence
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
