<FORM>
RAI                           Moves                            RAI                          Moves
BESP1                         1                                ESPj1                        3–2
BESP2                         1–3                              ESPj2                        1–3
BESP3                         3                                ESPj3                        1–2–3–1–2–3–2–1
BESP4                         1–3                              ESPj4                        1–2–3
BESP5                         1–3–1–2–3                        ESPj5                        1–2–1–3
BESP6                         1–3                              ESPj6                        1–2–3
BESP7                         1–3                              ESPj7                        1–2–1–2–3
BESP8                         3                                ESPj8                        1–2–1–2–3
BESP9                         1–2                              ESPj9                        1–2–1–2–1–2–1–2–1–3–1–2–3
BESP10                        1–2–1–3                          ESPj10                       1–2–3
</FORM>
<TEXT>
of the introductions contain a single move: BESP1 only contains Move 1 whereas BESP3 and BESP8 only contain Move 3. None of them follow a strict M1–M2–M3 sequence. The only sequence that is repeated is M1–M3, which occurs four times. In summary, RAIs in The ESPecialist do not seem to follow a pattern in the organization of their rhetorical moves although there seems to be a preference for the M1–M3 type. In this type of structural organization, the authors establish a territory (by making topic generalizations and giving background information, for example) and then present their current study (by announcing the present research and indicating the structure of the article, for example). The ESPj RAIs, on the other hand, follow the pattern proposed by the CARS model more closely. Three of them follow the M1–M2–M3 sequence strictly while five others (i.e., ESPj3, ESPj5, ESPj7, ESPj8 and ESPj9) contain this sequence plus a repetition of one or more moves. Among these, ESPj5, ESPj7 and ESPj8 show very little variation from the canonical sequence: ESPj5 contains a one-sentence Move 1 between a 7-sentence Move 2 and a 7-sentence Move 3 while ESPj7 and ESPj8 each contain two instances of Move 2, establishing the niche in two separate installments. With the exception of ESPj2, all the RAIs in this corpus contain a Move 2, and there was only one instance (i.e., ESPj1) of Move 3-fronting. ESPj1 did not contain a Move 1 either, being, overall, the introduction that was the most dissimilar from the model.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
4. Discussion
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
The findings reported above seem to suggest that there are important differences in the rhetorical organi- zation of introductions in Brazilian Portuguese articles from The ESPecialist and articles from English for Specific Purposes. While the latter fits the proposed moves in the CARS model closely, the former has been shown to vary from it somewhat. It is worth noting that both journals specialize in the same subfield of Applied Linguistics, a claim supported not only by the names of these journals, but also by the similar editorial policies they hold (see Appendix C). Even though English for Specific Purposes reaches a wider inter- national readership by being published in English, the current academic lingua franca (Duszak & Lewkowicz, 2008), both journals started publication in the same year and can, therefore, be considered to have a similar level of maturity and tradition, at least in the eyes of the audience they reach. In this sense, the distinction made by Samraj (2005) between established fields and emerging fields of inquiry would not help explain the differences between the two sets of introductions analyzed in this study. It seems, thus, that the differences found would have to be attributed to cross-linguistic/cross-cultural reasons. The most striking difference between the BESP and the ESPj RAIs lies in the pervasive absence of Move 2 in the former. Other studies that looked at RAIs in languages other than English have found a similar pattern. As mentioned above, Jogthong (2001) reported an absence of Move 2 in 45% of the Thai articles studied while in Ahmad’s (1997) corpus of Malay RAIs 35% lacked a Move 2. In the present study, 70% of the RAIs in Portuguese did not contain this move, while only 10% of those in English lacked it.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_HEADER>
244
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                     E. Hirano/English  for Specific Purposes 28 (2009) 240–250
Table 3
Move  structure of the RAIs.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
