<TITLE>
Advisor Approval Form – Fall 2016
</TITLE>
<TEXT>
1. View your Enrollment Date in myCUInfo, myCUInfo.colorado.edu. The enrollment date indicates your specific time to register for classes. Assigned enrollment dates are generally during November for the spring semester and April for the fall semester. You can view course registration instructions and important academic deadlines on the Registrar’s Office website. www.colorado.edu/registrar/students/registration www.colorado.edu/registrar/students/academic-calendar
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
3. Degree audits are available through myCUInfo under Track your Academic Progress. This shows completed coursework and remaining requirements needed for your degree program. Review your degree audit prior to your advising appointment. (Keep in mind the degree audit is an unofficial document that may not be complete or up-to-date. Please contact Victoria Ibarra with concerns/errors.)
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
4. Submit your Advisor Approval form to the Undergraduate Studies Office, room C109, at least one day prior to your Enrollment Date. A completed and signed form is necessary to remove the Academic Advising Required Hold on your account. You will not be able to register for classes until this hold and/or any other campus hold are removed. Any incomplete forms will be returned.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
5. In planning your next semester schedule, keep in mind the Ensemble Rule that states all students registered for applied music lessons must be enrolled in an ensemble according to their degree program. Ensemble selection appropriate to your degree and scholarship agreement should be discussed with your advisor. You may be dropped from lessons and/or your music scholarship may be affected if you do not adhere to the Ensemble Rule set forth by the College of Music.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Name                                                                     Student Number
Enrollment  Date                                 Time                          Degree:    BA  □     BME   □    BM   □
Instrument / Voice                                             Applied  Instructor
Applied lesson level for Fall 2016:  FR  □      SO  □     JR  □       SR  □      NO  LESSONS    □
Credit hours of applied lessons ( check degree plan): 2 □ 3 □       4 □
Are you completing  one of the following for Fall 2016 ( check degree plan)? YES □  NO  □
</FORM>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                           BM  students: Applied Instruction Professor
                                            BME   students: Music Education Advisor
                                           BA  students: Victoria Ibarra, Staff Advisor
                         Please  print and  write legibly. Incomplete   forms   will not be accepted.
Sophomore    Proficiency □       Junior Recital □       Senior  Recital □       Senior Thesis  □               (credits)
Student  Signature                                                                             Date
Advisor  Signature                                                                             Date
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
