<TITLE>
Credit Card Authorization Form
</TITLE>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Here’s How Recurring Payments Work:
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
I ____________________________ authorize the Roseville Area Chamber of Commerce to charge (print full name) my credit card on the TBD by Chamber of each (circle one) month/qtr. for membership investments (day or date) and/or for purposes of keeping on file for event and other chamber related offerings/charges. Rafal Cieslak
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Checking          Savings                   Visa                 MasterCard
Name  on Acct    Rafal Cieslak                  Amex                 Discover
                JPMorgan    Chase
Bank Name                                    Cardholder Name
Account Number 01 2310  670  0 000           Card Number
Bank Routing #    101000048                  Card Code
Bank City/State   NY                         Exp. Date
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
SIGNATURE
</SECTION_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
I understand  that this authorization will remain in effect until I cancel it in writing, and I agree to notify the Roseville Area Chamber  of Commerce    of any
changes   in my account  information  or termination  of this authorization at least 30 days prior to the next billing date. I understand that if it is my first year
of membership    that the remaining   balance  associated   to my  account  will become   immediately   due  upon  receipt of my   termination. For  terminations
after my  first year, I understand that after the 30-days  the remaining   balance  is dropped  and  no  further sums  will be due. If the above  noted  payment
dates  fall on a weekend  or holiday, I understand  that the payments   may  be  executed  on  the next business  day.  For ACH   debits to my  checking/savings
account,  I understand   that because   these  are electronic transactions,  these  funds  may  be  withdrawn   from my   account  as soon   as the above   noted
periodic transaction  dates.  In the case  of an  ACH   Transaction   being  rejected for Non   Sufficient Funds  (NSF)   I understand   that the Roseville  Area
Chamber    of Commerce     may  at its discretion attempt  to process   the charge   again within  30 days,  and  agree  to an  additional $10   charge  for each
attempt  returned  NSF,  which  will be initiated as a separate transaction from  the authorized  recurring payment.   In the event  the account  has insufficient
funds  for a credit card  or payment   charge,  I understand   that my  account   will be charged   or debited  for two months.   In the event  the  account  has
insufficient funds twice in a 12-month   period or has  been  closed, or the credit charge  has been  declined  twice in a 12 month   period, this agreement   will
be deemed    in default and the remaining  balance   of my account  will become   immediately  due.  I acknowledge   that the origination of ACH  transactions  to
my  account  must   comply  with the  provisions  of U.S. law.  I certify that I am an authorized   user of this credit card/bank  account   and  will not dispute
these  scheduled  transactions  with my  bank  or credit card company;    so long as  the transactions  correspond   to the terms indicated  in this authorization
form. The  prevailing party in any action  of proceeding  to enforce the  terms of this agreement   shall be entitled to an award  of reasonable  attorneys’ fees
and  costs incurred.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                                                     650 Douglas Blvd.
                                                                   Roseville, CA 95678
                                                                     Tel 916.783.8136
                                                                     Fax 916.783.4772
Company Name      Amazon                     Member#      8799945
Billing Address 645 Madison  Ave             Phone#   (231)271-3881
City, State, Zip New York NY 10022 USA        Email  rcieslak@largo.com
    Checking/  Savings  Account                        Credit Card
INCLUDE  IN FIRST MONTH’S  INSTALLMENT  ONLY: ❑  $10 Building Fund     ❑$10  RABPAC
                                                          DATE  03-03-2020
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
