<FORM>
EMPLOYEE  ID                   LAST NAME                     FIRST NAME                 MIDDLE NAME
  HIRING DEPARTMENT/I.D.                    SUPERVISOR’S NAME                      SUPERVISOR’S EXT
       LEVEL (A,B, C)                        HOURLY  RATE                           MAX HOURS/WEEK
</FORM>
<FORM>
/
EFFECTIVE START DATE               REC #           PS POSITION NUMBER    /   JOB CODE                        END DATE
  STUDENT    ASSISTANT    (NON-WORK      STUDY)
                                                                         /
 EFFECTIVE START DATE              REC #           PS POSITION NUMBER     /  JOB CODE                        END DATE
                                                                         /
 EFFECTIVE START DATE              REC #           PS POSITION NUMBER     /  JOB CODE                        END DATE
 APPROPRIATE ADMINISTRATOR/APPROVAL NAME          APPROPRIATE ADMINISTRATOR/APPROVAL SIGNATURE               DATE
</FORM>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
STUDENT EMPLOYEE SIGNATURE
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
STUDENT EMPLOYEE PRINT NAME
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
DATE
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
STUDENT EMPLOYMENT PAYROLL TRANSACTION FORM (SEPTF)
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
SECTION     1: TYPE   OF  ACTION
         New  Appointment               Prior Employee                  Concurrent   Appointment
         Position Change:  Transfer  to another  Department   and/or  change  PeopleSoft   Position Number
         Hourly Rate  Change:  *Note:  No  retroactive  pay/changes    accepted.
                 Merit  Salary Increase  (5% Max)  (must  include  Student  Performance   Report)
                 Other:  Change  in job responsibilities (must include  letter with change  of job duties)
         Separation:  Student  is no longer a CSULB  employee   or no longer  working  for the department.
SECTION     2: APPOINTMENT        INFORMATION        (to  be completed     by the  Hiring  Department)
                                FEDERAL     WORK    STUDY    JOB  #:
    WORK-STUDY
      1)  Are you currently working for another department or position (not including this position)?
          YES      NO      If yes, which            -     -     -    -     -         many        -    -     -         box  Work-Study
                                        department?                             How        hours?               Check    if
      2)  Are you currently on a visa or work authorization? YES       NO       If yes, enter visa type:
 In accepting this employment, I agree to abide by all CSULB system policies including being enrolled in at least 6 units for
 undergrad/graduates   per semester and may  not be employed  more than  20 hours per week during academic  term.
 International students on a visa are required by the Immigration and Naturalization Service to maintain a specific amount of units for
 undergrad/graduate.  For more  information regarding this requirement, please contact Center for International Education Office. I am a
 student at CSU, Long Beach and  all statements made are true and complete to the best of my knowledge. I understand that any false
 statement  on this form may be grounds fortermination.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
