<SECTION_HEADER>
IV. CONCLUSIONS AND DISCUSSION
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
What is the purpose of a RA and what makes it a good one, and who decides that it is a good RA? Are there rules for easier writing? If the main function of a RA is to transfer a new knowledge on a research topic, then a good paper is the one that is clear, coherent, focused, well argued and uses language that does not have ambiguous or equivoque meaning. However, it is not only the message that is important. The RA must have a well-defined structure and function in serve like a cook-book, so the others can reproduce and repeat explained experiments. Answer research questions Give summary conclusions There are some rules that can make the writing and publishing of RAs 'easier'. Here, we summarised some 'golden' rules that should always be in the mind of an inexperienced researcher (Table 3). We put all these together to make a final list of some 40 logical steps, which can be find in the Appendix.
</TEXT>
<TABLE>
NAME                               GOLDEN      RULE
TAKE    A READER'S     VIEW        Write  for your audience not for yourself.
TELL   A  STORY                    Direct your RA   but keep a clear focus in the paper and present only
                                   results that relate to it.
BE  YOURSELF                       Write  like you speak and then revise and polish.
MAKE    IT  SIMPLE                 Use  simple(st) examples to explain complex  methodology.
                                   Use  concrete words  and strong verbs, avoid noun clusters (more
MAKE    IT  CONCRETE
                                   than three words), abstract and ambiguous  words.
                                   Avoid  redundancy,  repetition and over-explanation of familiar
MAKE    IT  SHORT                  techniques  and terminology.
TAKE    RESPONSIBILITY             Make   a clear distinction between your work and that of others.
MAKE    STRONG
STATEMENTS                         "We  concluded    " instead of "It may be concluded   "
BE  SELF-CRITICAL                  Consider  uncertainty of conclusions and their implications and
                                   acknowledge   the work  of others.
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
Although, it was assumed that the 'thicker' articles with wider range of vocabulary is preferable in the editors hands, the editors (and probably the readers) prefer simple, clear and coherent writing, rather than a fancy or complex, pseudo-scientific style. Also Funkhouser and Maccoby (1971) showed that the information gain is especially enhanced by the “use of examples", i.e. it helps a lot to use some non-science material, such as everyday life parallels, historical points, etc. On the other hand, some sections, such as Introduction and Discussion, have to intrigue readers and attract interest and should therefore not be over-simplified. For example, a mysterious title can catch readers' attention and will be easily remembered (e.g.: T.Y. Li and J. Yorke named their famous paper on chaos: "The period three means chaos"). Some sections require more skill and are more important. It is approximated that from all published journal RAs in the world, only less than 5% are read in detail. However, more than 50% of abstracts are read and so the quality of an abstracts is much more important (Gordon, 1983). Therefore, the abstract should present the 'story' of the RA in miniature and should be readable standalone.
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Unexpected
findings
                                                        6
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
