<SECTION_HEADER>
Fig. 4.5: Costs of cancer medicines (a) without and (b) with adjustment for purchasing power
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
a. Monthly  costs in 2016 US$  (exchange   rate)            b. Monthly  costs in 2016 US$  (purchasing   power
                                                              parity)
</FORM>
<TEXT>
To further illustrate the possible association between stronger price regulations and lower medicine prices, an analysis was undertaken to compare the real price indices for pharmaceuticals in Australia and the USA from 1981 to 2017. This index indicates the change in price level for pharmaceuticals relative to the change in price level for all goods and services (i.e. all-item consumer price index) against a nominated baseline year (i.e. 1981). These two countries were chosen for illustrative purpose because of their contrasting health care systems and approaches for managing medicine prices: the Australian Government is known to have implemented a range of pricing policies for medicines over the past decades for its single-payer national pharmaceutical insurance scheme – the PBS; the USA on the other hand is known for its market-based health care, with multiple private and public insurers and with minimal government intervention for the pricing of medicines.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
prices of pharmaceuticals grew faster than the collective prices of all goods and services (Fig. 4.6a, p.61). However, the trends in the two countries began to diverge in the late 1980s where the price level of medicines continued to rise faster in the USA, while the growth rate of pharmaceutical prices in Australia seemed to have been stabilized at around 10% higher than the consumer price index. This could possibly be due to the introduction of “cost effectiveness” as a requirement before listing a medicine on the national pharmaceutical insurance scheme, so as to ensure the benefits of a given medicine were high enough to justify the price requested by the manufacturer (246). The divergence became more prominent when the Australian Government undertook further reforms of its national scheme after 2005 (247), which was implemented in response to a report that warned “in 40 years’ time, the PBS could account for 3.4% of GDP, making it the largest part of the Government’s spending on health” (248). The reforms seem to have resulted in gradual normalization of the growth rate of medicine prices in Australia to a level in line with the overall inflation rate of other consumer goods (Fig. 4.6a). In contrast, medicine prices continued to grow considerably in the USA, with the cumulative growth reaching 2.4 times the overall inflation rate of other consumer goods in 2017. Of note, the price level of prescription medicines in the USA rose in parallel with Pricing and reimbursement policies in Australia over four decades have controlled the growth rate of medicine prices.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
60
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_BREAK>
