<TABLE>
System               Examples   of disorders, conditions,  and
                     symptoms
Neurological         Stroke, dementia, Parkinson  disease, seizure
                     disorders, headache  disorders, traumatic
                     brain injury, peripheral neuropathy, chronic
                     pain disorders, neuromuscular  disorders
Cardiovascular       Angina,  congestive heart failure, dyspnea,
                     dysrhythmias
Pulmonary            COPD,   emphysema,   asthma,  laryngospasm
Digestive            Reflux, peptic ulcer disease, cholelithiasis,
                     colitis, irritable bowel syndrome
Genitourinary        Incontinence, benign  prostatic hypertrophy,
                     nocturia, enuresis, interstitial cystitis
Endocrine            Hypothyroidism,   hyperthyroidism,  diabetes
                     mellitus
Musculoskeletal      Rheumatoid   arthritis, osteoarthritis,
                     fibromyalgia, Sjögren  syndrome,  kyphosis
Reproductive         Pregnancy,  menopause,   menstrual cycle
                     variations
Sleep disorders      Obstructive sleep apnea,  central sleep
                     apnea, restless legs syndrome, periodic limb
                     movement   disorder, circadian rhythm  sleep
                     disorders, parasomnias
Other                Allergies, rhinitis, sinusitis, bruxism,
                     alcohol and other substance  use/dependence/
                     withdrawal
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
Table 6—Common Comorbid Psychiatric Disorders and Symptoms II. Pre-Sleep Conditions: Patients with insomnia may de- velop behaviors that have the unintended consequence of per- petuating their sleep problem. These behaviors may begin as strategies to combat the sleep problem, such as spending more time in bed in an effort to “catch up” on sleep. Other behaviors in bed or in the bedroom that are incompatible with sleep may include talking on the telephone, watching television, computer use, exercising, eating, smoking, or “clock watching.” Insom- nia patients may report sensations of being more aware of the environment than are other individuals and may report antici- pating a poor sleep hours before bedtime, and become more alert and anxious as bedtime approaches. Characterization of the sleeping environment (couch/bed, light/dark, quiet/noisy, room temperature, alone/bed partner, TV on/off) as well as the patient’s state of mind (sleepy vs. wide awake, relaxed vs. anx- ious) is helpful in understanding which factors might facilitate or prolong sleep onset or awakenings after sleep. III. Sleep-Wake Schedule: In evaluating sleep-related symptoms, the clinician must consider not only the patient’s “usual” symptoms, but also their range, day-to-day variability, and evolution over time. Specific sleep-wake variables such as
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
time to fall asleep (sleep latency), number of awakenings, wake time after sleep onset (WASO), sleep duration, and napping can be quantified retrospectively during the clinical assessment and prospectively with sleep-wake logs. Although no specific quan- titative sleep parameters define insomnia disorder, common complaints for insomnia patients are an average sleep latency >30 minutes, wake after sleep onset >30 minutes, sleep effi- ciency <85%, and/or total sleep time <6.5 hours.19,20 Day-to-day variability should be considered, as well as variability during longer periodicities such as those that may occur with the men- strual cycle or seasons. Patterns of sleep at unusual times may assist in identifying Circadian Rhythm Disorders such as Ad- vanced Sleep Phase Type or Delayed Sleep Phase Type. Assess- ing whether the final awakening occurs spontaneously or with an alarm adds insight into the patient’s sleep needs and natural sleep and wake rhythm. Finally, the clinician must ascertain whether the individual’s sleep and daytime complaints occur despite adequate time available for sleep, in order to distinguish insomnia from behaviorally induced insufficient sleep. IV. Nocturnal Symptoms: Patient and bed partner reports may also help to identify nocturnal signs, symptoms and behav- iors associated with breathing-related sleep disorders (snoring, gasping, coughing), sleep related movement disorders (kick- ing, restlessness), parasomnias (behaviors or vocalization), and comorbid medical/neurological disorders (reflux, palpitations, seizures, headaches). Other physical sensations and emotions associated with wakefulness (such as pain, restlessness, anxi- ety, frustration, sadness) may contribute to insomnia and should also be evaluated. V. Daytime Activities and Daytime Function: Daytime activities and behaviors may provide clues to potential causes and consequences of insomnia. Napping (frequency/day, times, voluntary/involuntary), work (work times, work type such as driving or with dangerous consequences, disabled, caretaker responsibilities), lifestyle (sedentary/active, home- bound, light exposure, exercise), travel (especially across time zones), daytime dysfunction (quality of life, mood, cog- nitive dysfunction), and exacerbation of comorbid disorders should be evaluated in depth. Common daytime consequences include:
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
• Fatigue and sleepiness. Feelings of fatigue (low energy, physical tiredness, weariness) are more common than symptoms of sleepiness (actual tendency to fall asleep) in patients with chronic insomnia. The presence of significant sleepiness should prompt a search for other potential sleep disorders. The number, duration, and timing of naps should be thoroughly investigated, as both a consequence of in- somnia and a potential contributing factor.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Examples
Major  depressive disorder, bipolar mood   disorder, dysthymia
Generalized  anxiety disorder, panic disorder, posttraumatic  stress disorder,
obsessive  compulsive  disorder
Schizophrenia,  schizoaffective disorder
Alzheimer   disease, other dementias
Attention deficit disorder
Adjustment   disorders, personality disorders, bereavement,  stress
</FORM>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
Journal of Clinical Sleep Medicine, Vol. 4, No. 5, 2008
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
S Schutte-Rodin, L Broch, D Buysse et al
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Psychotic disorders
Amnestic  disorders
Disorders usually seen in childhood and adolescence
Other disorders and symptoms
                                                                      492
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
