<SECTION_HEADER>
Background Screening Disclosure
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
I hereby authorize InSource Employment Screening Services and its designated agents and representatives to conduct a comprehensive review of my background through a consumer report to be generated for volunteer, employment, promotion, reassignment or retention as an employee. I understand that the scope of the consumer report may include, but is not limited to, the following areas: names and dates of previous/current employment, work experience, worker’s compensation claims, criminal history records (from local, state, federal, international and other law enforcement agencies’ records), sexual offender’s lists, wants and warrants records, motor vehicle records, military records, educational verification, license verification, credit history, civil cases, OIG/GSA, OFAC/patriots act, any sanction lists, FBI finger printing and drug testing. Upon Request, InSource Employment Screening Services, P.O. Box 1682, Suffolk, VA 23439, 757.378.0064, will supply a copy of the completed consumer report along with a copy of an individual’s rights under the Fair Credit Reporting Act.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Authorization and Release
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
I, _________________________, authorize the complete release of these records or data pertaining to me which an individual, company, firm, corporation, or public agency may have. I authorize the full release of the information described above, without any reservation, throughout any duration of my employment at ________________________ (company name). I certify that all information provided below and on my resume is correct to the best of my knowledge. Any false statements provided in this form and my resume will be considered just cause for the termination of employment at any time. This authorization and consent shall be valid in original, fax, or copy form. Dan Bliss Amazon
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Signature:                                                                  Date: 02-04-2020
Applicant’s Name:      Sarah                                                 tanugi
         (Please print)    First                    Middle                    Last
Other names  used (e.g., maiden name):           Sarah                              Jones
                          (Please print)            First            Middle            Last
Date of Birth: 03-05-2020                 Social Security Number:  254016713
Driver’s License Number    5958098                  State       IL
Current Address:    8915   N  ALLEN     RD   PEORIA      IL 61615    America
</FORM>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                  DISCLOSURE    AND  RELEASE    AUTHORIZATION     FORM
For California, Minnesota, New York and Oklahoma applicants only:
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
<TEXT>
 You may limit “prescreened” offers of credit and insurance you get based on information in your credit report. Unsolicited “prescreened” offers for credit and insurance must include a toll- free phone number you can call if you choose to remove your name and address from the lists these offers are based on. You may opt-out with the nationwide credit bureaus at 1-888-5- OPTOUT (1-888-567-8688).
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 You may seek damages from violators. If a consumer reporting agency, or, in some cases, a user of consumer reports or a furnisher of information to a consumer reporting agency violates the FCRA, you may be able to sue in state or federal court.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
States may enforce the FCRA, and many states have their own consumer reporting laws. In some cases, you may have more rights under state law. For more information, contact your state or local consumer protection agency or your state Attorney General. Federal enforcers are:
</TEXT>
<FORM>
TYPE   OF  BUSINESS:                                     CONTACT:
Consumer   reporting agencies, creditors and others not  Federal Trade Commission:   Consumer  Response  Center -
listed below                                             FCRA
                                                         Washington,  DC  20580 1-877-382-4357
National banks, federal branches/agencies of foreign     Office of the Comptroller of the Currency
banks (word                                              Compliance  Management,   Mail Stop 6-6
"National" or initials "N.A." appear in or after bank's  Washington,  DC  20219 800-613-6743
name)
Federal Reserve System  member   banks (except           Federal Reserve Consumer   Help (FRCH)
national banks,                                          P O Box  1200
and federal branches/agencies of foreign banks)          Minneapolis, MN   55480
                                                         Telephone: 888-851-1920
                                                         Website Address: www.federalreserveconsumerhelp.gov
                                                         Email Address: ConsumerHelp@FederalReserve.gov
Savings associations and federally chartered savings     Office of Thrift Supervision
banks (word  "Federal" or initials "F.S.B." appear in    Consumer   Complaints
federal institution's name)                              Washington,  DC  20552 800-842-6929
Federal credit unions (words "Federal Credit Union"      National Credit Union Administration
appear in                                                1775 Duke  Street
institution's name)                                      Alexandria, VA  22314 703-519-4600
State-chartered banks that are not members of the        Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation
Federal Reserve                                          Consumer   Response Center, 2345  Grand Avenue,  Suite
System                                                   100
                                                         Kansas  City, Missouri 64108-2638 1-877-275-3342
Air, surface, or rail common carriers regulated by       Department  of Transportation , Office of Financial
former Civil                                             Management
Aeronautics Board  or Interstate Commerce                Washington,  DC  20590 202-366-1306
Commission
Activities subject to the Packers and Stockyards Act,    Department  of Agriculture
1921                                                     Office of Deputy Administrator - GIPSA
                                                         Washington,  DC  20250 202-720-7051
</FORM>
<PAGE_BREAK>
