<SECTION_HEADER>
Review
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TABLE>
Chloroquine       Options†             Sites of action
resistance*
Yes               Atovaquone-          Blood stage (suppressive) and liver
                  proguanil or         stage (causal)‡
                  doxycycline or       Blood stage (suppressive)
                  mefloquine§  or      Blood stage (suppressive)
                  primaquine||         Liver stage (causal) and blood stage¶
No                Chloroquine or       Blood stage (suppressive)
                  atovaquone-          Blood stage (suppressive) and liver
                  proguanil or         stage (causal)
                  doxycycline or       Blood stage (suppressive)
                  mefloquine  or       Blood stage (suppressive)
                  primaquine¶          Liver stage (causal) and blood stage**
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
Pvivaxhas been widely identified in Indonesia, Papua New Guinea, and sporadic cases in other Asian countries. Many countries with both urban and rural malaria transmission may not have malaria risk in the most frequently visited major cities. †Equal efficacy; choice depends on traveller, itinerary, side-effects, individual choices, and convenience. ‡Tafenoquine and atovaquone can act also on the liver stage; doxycycline, azithromycin, and proguanil have limited activity in the liver stage. §Not recommended for travelling to Thailand borders with Cambodia and Burma due to mefloquine resistance. ||Need to check G6PD level before prescribing. Sometimes used as terminal prophylaxis in travellers with prolonged stays in countries with P vivaxor P ovale to eliminate the hypnozoite stage in the liver. ¶Primaquine has an effect on the liver-stage (primary schizont) of all four plasmodium species, and the sexual blood stages of all four species but only the asexual blood stages of P vivaxbut not Pfalciparum.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Epidemiology of imported malaria and malaria risk in travellers
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
The estimated risk for a traveller acquiring malaria differs markedly from area to area.2,36,37,45,46 This variability is a function of the intensity of transmission within the various regions, the season of travel, and of the itinerary and type of travel.36,37 Ongoing malaria transmission occurs in large areas of Central and South America, Hispaniola, Africa, the Indian subcontinent, southeast Asia, the middle east, eastern Europe, and the south Pacific islands.1,2,5,10,35,36,43,44 There has been a marked increased in tourism, immigration, and refugee, student, and business travel to these malaria-endemic areas.25,30,47 International migration has risen from 120 million in 1990 to 175 million in 2002.28 Non- immune individuals are particularly susceptible to develop severe malaria if exposed to an infected mosquito, particularly in areas with high levels of transmission.2,5,14,19,36,45,46 Some groups are at higher risk. Immigrants to developed countries who are returning to homes and families in endemic countries (visiting friends and relatives) are at much higher risk of acquiring malaria.24,30–33 Indeed, this particular group of travellers is responsible for a high volume of international travellers and experience excessive rates of travel-related morbidity including malaria and its
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
complications.31,33 Many   of  them   have   not  received
malaria  chemoprophylaxis   and  are unaware   that clinical
immunity    to  malaria,   even   if intensively  exposed
previously at some  point in their life, wanes over a short
period of time.31 In addition, stigma  associated with the
acquisition of malaria  and  the perceived  incompetence
of physicians in the developed  world by some  immigrant
groups   affect  their  malaria   preventive   decisions.34
Furthermore,   low insurance  coverage,  misperception   of
disease  risk, and   the health-care   provider’s level  of
knowledge    of travel  medicine   may   impact   pretravel
malaria recommendations.32    Immigrants   visiting friends
and  relatives frequently   are prescribed   inappropriate
prophylaxis  or receive  not at all. In addition, many   of
them  may   be at higher  risk of acquiring  malaria since
they    may     decide     to   non-adhere      to    their
chemoprophylactic    drug regimen,   have prolonged   stays
in their country  of  origin, or spend  time  in high-risk
areas without  taking  any  personal  protective measures
against malaria.30–34
  International  tourist arrivals  to sub-Saharan   Africa
increased  from  6·7 million  to 17 million between   1990
and   2000.48  Approximately     30 000   travellers  from
industrialised  countries   contract  malaria  each   year,
predominantly     travellers from    Europe   and    North
America.  The  risk of malaria  is higher for travellers to
Oceania   and   sub-Saharan    Africa,  particularly  west
Africa.20,22,24,26,27,30 The proportion of malaria cases caused
by  particular plasmodia   species reflects the  traveller’s
destinations.   However,    given    that  most    malaria
infections  in the  world  are due   to P  falciparum  and
P  vivax, imported  malaria  cases  are caused  mainly  by
these  two  species.36,49–51 Only a few cases of imported
malaria  cases due to P malariae  and P ovale are reported
annually.17,52 When    malaria    cases  are   caused   by
P  falciparum  the overall case  fatality rate varies from
0·6%   to  3·8%.4,16,21 In most  reported   fatal cases  of
imported  malaria, travellers failed to use or comply with
antimalarial  prophylaxis.4,16,21 It is generally agreed that
the clinical features, outcome,   and  severity of malaria
depend   upon   the level of background    immunity.45  In
areas of high stable transmission,  the clinical signs and
symptoms    are confined  to childhood. At  lower levels of
transmission   a broader age  range  becomes   susceptible,
and  at low or unstable levels of transmission, or in non-
immune      travellers, malaria    is  symptomatic     and
therefore P  falciparum infection  is potentially lethal for
travellers at all ages.5,36,45 Approximately 1% of all non-
immune    travellers who acquire P falciparum  infection in
high-risk  areas  die.14,16,21 This risk is proportional to
delays  in seeking   and  receiving  appropriate   medical
care.14,16,21
  Estimating  the  risk for infection for various types  of
travellers is difficult and can be  substantially different
even  for people who   travel or reside temporarily in the
same  general  areas within a country.43,44,50 The estimated
risk for a traveller contracting malaria differs from area
</UNSPECIFIED>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                          *Resistance to chloroquine is based on P falciparum. However, chloroquine-resistant
140                                                                                                                                                                     http://infection.thelancet.com      Vol  6   March   2006
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
