<SECTION_HEADER>
ARTICLE
</SECTION_HEADER>
<SECTION_HEADER>
ABSTRACT
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
In the Biomedical sector, the current applications of data mining are the most successful and they have become the subfield of medical research. The basis for this growth is that nowadays most of the health related data are stored in small datasets scattered through various Hospitals, Clinics and Research centers. The healthcare sector is presently facing both the economic predictability and the methodological prospect of a data based approach for quality administration. Hence, abundant data mining techniques have been proposed to process medical data stream. Applying data mining techniques to the centralized database will offer to doctors investigative and foretelling tools from the surface of the data. Modern clinical practices also undertake transformation not only in diagnosis and treatment methods, but also in understanding of health and illness concepts. Data Mining can generate information that can be useful to all stakeholders in health care, including patients by identifying effective treatments and best practices. Though data mining methods and tools have been applied in diverse areas for more than 40 years already, their applications in healthcare are comparatively young. Therefore, this paper presents a survey on the significance of Data Mining techniques in Disease Diagnosis and Biomedical Research.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
INTRODUCTION
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
Infection Practically in every country, the cost of healthcare is increasing more rapidly than  the readiness
and  the capability to pay for it. At the same time, more and more data is being obtained  around  healthcare
processes   in the form  of Electronic  Health  Records  (EHR),  health  insurance  claims, medical   imaging
databases,  disease  registries, spontaneous  reporting sites, and clinical trials. As a result, data mining has
become   important  to the healthcare  world. On  the one  hand, EHR  offers the data  that gets data  miners
excited. However,  on the other hand,  it is accompanied  by challenges such  as 1) the unavailability of large
sources  of data to academic   researchers,  and 2) limited access  to data-mining  experts  [6]. But, still the
quality of health care  service at a cheap  cost  continues  to be a  difficult issue in developing countries.
Although  several countries have  taken  firm steps in providing aid services, the reach of those services  to
the poor, still remains as a  difficulty. In different dimensions, un-imaginable  services like separation  of
dual births, discovery  of latest medicines  for deadly diseases  are  happening.  However,   a few  cases  of
death  occur  due to   poor  clinical diagnosing system   and inadequate   treatment.  Most  of the time, the
clinical selections are created by  the doctor’s experience  and  skill. Hospitals do have info systems,  call
Support  Systems,  Image  and  Scan  process systems.  However,  all hospitals do not have  these facilities or
their applications are restricted.
Call support systems  with diagnosing  support  for naive doctors and for knowledgeable   doctors would  be a
tenet for higher clinical cognitive process. The primary initiative is that the prospective costs and effects of
diagnosis  can be  measured   and  used  to enhance   the task. Furthermore,   the transitional enquiry steps
such  as asking for more  systematic  studies, or more examination   done  by human   professionals, can  also
be  computed   in terms  of  cost and  effect. Based  on  these  cost  and  effect, the system  can  learn  to
recommend    the  optimal action. Providing  precious services  at cheap  prices may   be a major  constraint
encountered   by the  aid organizations  (hospitals, medical centers). Valuable  quality service denotes  the
correct diagnosing   of patients  and  providing  economical   treatment.  Acceptable   computer-based    info
and/or  call support systems  will aid in achieving clinical tests at a reduced value. Due to the accessibility
of integrated  info through  huge  patient  repositories, there is a  swing  within the insight of clinicians,
</FORM>
<TEXT>
their applications are restricted. Call support systems with diagnosing support for naive doctors and for knowledgeable doctors would be a tenet for higher clinical cognitive process. The primary initiative is that the prospective costs and effects of diagnosis can be measured and used to enhance the task. Furthermore, the transitional enquiry steps such as asking for more systematic studies, or more examination done by human professionals, can also be computed in terms of cost and effect. Based on these cost and effect, the system can learn to recommend the optimal action. Providing precious services at cheap prices may be a major constraint encountered by the aid organizations (hospitals, medical centers). Valuable quality service denotes the correct diagnosing of patients and providing economical treatment. Acceptable computer-based info and/or call support systems will aid in achieving clinical tests at a reduced value. Due to the accessibility of integrated info through huge patient repositories, there is a swing within the insight of clinicians, patients and payers from qualitative health care sectors.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
President Obama has recently expressed a strong conviction that “Science offers great potential for improving health”. The President has announced a research initiative that aims to accelerate progress toward a new era of precision medicine. The time is accurate for this idealistic initiative, and the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and other partners will work to attain this vision [7]. The concept of precision medicine speaks of prevention and treatment strategies that take individual variability into account. Even though it is not new, the impact of practicality is still deprived. If one considers blood typing, for instance, has been used to guide blood transfusions for more than a century. But the vision of applying this concept broadly has been intensely improved by the latest development of large-scale biologic databases (such as the human genome sequence), powerful methods for typifying patients (such as proteomics, metabolomics, genomics, diverse cellular assays, and even mobile health technology), and computational tools for analyzing large sets of data. Francis S.Collins et al. stated that, “What is necessary now is a broad
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
| Lakshmipathy & Ranganathan. 2016 | IIOABJ | Vol. 7 | Suppl 1 | 284-292 |
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
284
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
SUPPLEMENT ISSUE
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
         SIGNIFICANCE                        OF      DATA           MINING             TECHNIQUES                        IN    DISEASE
              DIAGNOSIS                    AND         BIOMEDICAL                      RESEARCH                    –   A   SURVEY
                                 Thara      Lakshmipathy1           and    Gunasundari          Ranganathan2
       KEY WORDS
data  mining techniques;
 diagnosis; health care
    sector; medical
diagnosis; classification;
      decision tree.
   Published: 2 Nov 2016
                                                                                                                                                                     SCIENCE
                                                                                                                                                                     COMPUTER
        www.iioab.org
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
