<TITLE>
Credit Card Authorization for Payment of Life Premium
</TITLE>
<FORM>
Credit card number 4 0 6 7 4 1 7 4 7  7 4  9 7  1 9  0      Expiration date 0 2 2 0  2  2
                      0      0                                           Month Year
Amount to charge $ 5      0
Identification Number 8 3 0 2  5  3  2
Credit cardholder's billing address (Address where you receive your credit card statement)
   2 7 8 8   W  B l a c k s t o n e C r o s s i n g F a y e t t e v i l l e , A R 7 2 7 0 4
Credit cardholder's phone number 4 0 4 - 9 2 5 - 7 4 2 9  x 1 1 1
Email s i l a s .  k u p  h a  l @  h o  t m a  i l  . c  o m
Policy Number 6 4 3 8  7  2 4  8         Renewal Date 0 4   0  7   2  0 2  0
                                                     Day  Month Year
Policyholder’s name B e n e d i  c  t     K  u p  h  a  l
</FORM>
<TEXT>
By my signature on this document, I hereby authorize AMEDEX Insurance Company (Bermuda) to directly debit the credit card that I have identified above for the payment of insurance premiums for my AMEDEX Insurance Company (Bermuda) life insurance policy, as specifically identified hereinabove.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
I understand that, if there are any changes to my AMEDEX Insurance Company (Bermuda) life insurance policy, the amount of the premium may also change from the above-stated amount. I further understand that a true and correct copy of this Agreement will be forwarded to my credit card company and, by my signature on this agreement, I request and instruct them to allow AMEDEX Insurance Company (Bermuda) to directly debit my credit card account for the payment of life insurance premiums until such time as I instruct otherwise in writing.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
I acknowledge that, in the event that the direct debit of any life insurance premiums by credit card for my AMEDEX life insurance policy is rejected or declined for any reason, it will become my personal responsibility to immediately pay the premiums for my life insurance policy, or my policy may lapse, be terminated and/or cancelled.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Signature                                                     Date 09 07 2020
</FORM>
<UNSPECIFIED>
7001  Southwest 97th Avenue •  Miami, Florida 33173 • Telephone: (305) 275-1400 • Fax: (305) 275-8484 • Website: www.amedex.com   • E-mail: amedex @amedex.com
</UNSPECIFIED>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                                (cid:136) y              (cid:136) e
     Cardholder    Signature
                                                  AUTOMATIC           DEBIT    FOR    FUTURE      RENEWALS
     Please  send  this form  via fax  to expedite   the renewal   process   (305)  275-8484.
                                                                                                                                               Oficinas en Bermuda
                                                                                                Armoury  Building 1st Floor • 37 Reid Street • Hamilton HM12, Bermuda
Administrador
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
