<CAPTION>
Order Form Supplement for Einstein Features
</CAPTION>
<TEXT>
This Order Form Supplement forms a part of the Order Form between Customer and salesforce.com, inc. or one of its Affiliates (“SFDC”) under which Customer has purchased subscriptions to the Service which contains one or more elements of artificial intelligence functionality available for Customer’s active enablement at its choosing as a feature of such Service (each element, an “Einstein feature”). Such functionality is currently branded as Einstein. The infrastructure used by SFDC to host Customer Data submitted to an Einstein feature is provided in part by Amazon Web Services, Inc. (or such other infrastructure provider as identified in the Documentation for the applicable Einstein feature) and involves the storing and processing of Customer Data. This infrastructure provider may use different privacy and security protections, and be hosted in different physical locations, than the Services. Any privacy, security or physical data location commitments in Customer’s applicable master subscription agreement for the Services shall not apply to the portion(s) of an Einstein feature hosted on such infrastructure provider. Such portions shall instead be as described in the applicable Trust and Compliance Documentation. If Customer enables an Einstein feature in an instance or Org of the Services, such Einstein feature may be enabled across applicable SFDC services subscriptions in such instance, and may process Customer Data associated with such subscriptions, whether such subscriptions are purchased from SFDC or from a reseller.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
Customer acknowledges that SFDC may access Customer Data submitted to the Services and Einstein features for the purpose of improving and training similar or related services and features, and Customer instructs SFDC to process its Customer Data for such purpose, provided, however, SFDC will not share Customer's Customer Data with any other customers in connection with the foregoing. Customer retains all ownership of its Customer Data submitted to the Services and Einstein features and SFDC retains all ownership in and to all system performance data, machine learning algorithms, and aggregated results of such machine learning. Upon Customer’s first use of an Einstein feature in an instance of the Services, Customer will be presented with an In-App Message directing Customer to confirm acceptance of Einstein feature terms and conditions. Instructions for enabling/disabling each Einstein feature in any instance are outlined in the Documentation here: https://help.salesforce.com/articleView?id=admin_einstein_features_setup.htm&type=5. By accepting these terms and conditions on behalf of a Customer, you represent that you are authorized to bind such Company to these terms and conditions. If you are not authorized then you agree that you may not and will not attempt to enable any Einstein feature in Customer’s instance of the Services. Please provide Account Number(s) or Org ID(s) for all instances existing as of June 12, 2018 that you would like to have access to Einstein features. Instructions for locating Org IDs for your instances are available here: https://help.salesforce.com/articleView?id=000006019&type=1. Account numbers appear on SFDC invoices. Instances created on or after June 12, 2018 will be Einstein accessible and Org IDS for such instances do not need to be listed on an executed Supplement: __________________________________________________________
</TEXT>
<FORM>
CUSTOMER       (signed by authorized representative)  Customer   Name:
Signature:                                                     Title:  Manager
Print Name:   Joseph   Correa                                  Date:                        02-05-20
</FORM>
<PAGE_BREAK>
