<SECTION_HEADER>
4.2 Exclusion criteria
</SECTION_HEADER>
<SECTION_HEADER>
5. E XPOSURES/ INTERVENTIONS.
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
The methods of exposure assessment will be extracted and whether the method has been validated, the number of items in the questionnaires and the number of assessments. The duration of the exposure/intervention will be recorded as well as the time between exposure assessment/intervention and outcome assessment.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
5.1 Labels of exposure/interventions.
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
During data extraction, interventions/exposures will be labelled using the exposure codes listed in the Guidelines for the search literature reviews of the 2007 WCRF/AICR expert Report1 . The interventions/exposures are allocated under the main headings and subheadings listed in Appendix 4. For example, diet modifications –e.g. diets rich in fruit and vegetables and low in fats- will be coded under “Dietary patterns” and combinations of micronutrients in supplements will be coded under “Dietary Constituents”.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
An additional main heading for “Nutrition-related complementary and alternative Medicine” has been added for this review (code 9 in Appendix 4) with the following subheadings: Traditional medicine, Naturopathy, Phytotherapy, Homeopathy. Biomarkers of exposure will be extracted under the heading of the corresponding exposure, Biomarkers for which there is no evidence on appropriate validity and repeatability will not be included in the review (List of biomarkers is in Appendix 5).
</TEXT>
<FORM>
5.2 Timeframe   of exposure  assessment.
The  timeframe of exposure  assessment  in observational studies will be recorded as follows:
-Exposure  assessment  refers to a period before primary breast cancer diagnosis (childhood,
adolescence, adulthood).
-Exposure  assessment  refers to the period during therapy for primary breast cancer.
-Exposure  assessment  refers to a period after primary breast cancer diagnosis.
</FORM>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
)!
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
6. O UTCOME
!
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
