<TITLE>
AmeriFirst Home Mortgage ACH Auto Draft Payment Authorization Agreement
</TITLE>
<FORM>
Draft my account on the same day every month:  ☐  1st          ☐  5th          ☐ 10th         ☐  15th
Month  to begin draft: ☐Jan. ☐Feb. ☐Mar.   ☐Apr.   ☐May   ☐June   ☐July  ☐Aug.   ☐Sept.  ☐Oct.  ☐Nov.   ☐Dec.
Debit Account Information (Please Print)
Borrower Name(s)  Robert  Comi
Name  of Bank USA   Bank
ABA Routing Number  265378182
Account Number*  01  2320  105  1 003
</FORM>
<TEXT>
*Please note that the account number used by your financial institution for ACH may be different than what is shown on your check or savings deposit slip. If you are uncertain of the correct number to use, please contact your bank or credit union.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Account  Type            ☐  Checking               ☐  Savings
Payment  Amount   $ 12000                            Total Draft Amount  $ 12000
(Optional) I would like an additional $                       drafted each month and  applied to my principal balance.
</FORM>
<TEXT>
By submitting this application you authorize AmeriFirst Home Mortgage to draft the account specified above for the amount of your scheduled monthly mortgage payment due. In the event that your monthly payment increases due to increases in your escrow or interest rate (if applicable), you authorize us to increase the withdrawal by the amount of the increase. The ACH will not process for accounts that are prepaid. If your account becomes prepaid, the withdrawal will be paused until the loan is no longer paid ahead.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
I am aware, as the “originator” of this agreement, that I must notify AmeriFirst Home Mortgage of any changes or termination of this agreement at least 3 business days prior to the transaction date. I understand that it is my responsibility to maintain a balance in the above account to enable the transfer to be successfully made on the date indicated. If the set date falls on a non-business day (weekend or holiday), the transaction will occur on the next business day. I am aware that I will be assessed a fee if a successful transfer cannot be made in accordance with my instructions. AmeriFirst Home Mortgage reserves the right to terminate this agreement at any time, for any reason, including repeated returned transactions. By signing below, I am giving AmeriFirst Home Mortgage authority to commence, increase, decrease or terminate this origination upon a written or verbal request from me.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Borrower Signature                                           Date 12/4/2020
Co-Borrower Signature                                       Date 12/4/2020
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Please attach a voided check from your bank.
</SECTION_HEADER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
Loan Number _______________________ Date ______________________________ 2023020040 12/4/2020
</PAGE_HEADER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
Loan Number _______________________ Date ______________________________ 2023020040 12/4/2020
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Please send the completed form to AmeriFirst:
Fax:       269-585-5990
Email:  servicing@amerifirst.com
Mail:      AmeriFirst Home Mortgage
           950 Trade Centre Way, Suite 400
           Kalamazoo, MI 49002
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
