<TABLE>
Sown  area,
  Area, hectare            Number  of     In % to the total   thousand       In % of total
                        enterprises, units                    hectares           area
   All of them:              45613              100           19811,2            100
   20,0…  50,0               24596             53,9            548,3             2,8
   50,1…100,0                4606              10,1            338,2             1,7
  100,1…250,0                4713              10,3            774,1             3,9
  250,1…500,0                3232               7,1            1171,5            5,9
 500,1…1000,0                2925               6,4            2103,6            10,6
 1000,1…2000,0               2822               6,2            4045,7            20,4
 2000,1…3000,0               1277               2,8            3096,9            15,6
More  then 3000,0            1442               3,2            7732,9            39,1
</TABLE>
<PAGE_HEADER>
261
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
       It is concluded that the main agricultural enterprises in Ukraine are farms  with
an area of more than 3000  hectares. It occupy 39.1 %  of the total acreage, their number
at the same time  is only 3.2 % of the total number  of farms. Most  of these enterprises
are used in the cultivator processing system  for presowing  continuous  tillage.
       We  have investigated  that it is possible to increase the rate of work on surface
tillage (cultivation) by using new materials  that have high tribological properties and
do  not require maintenance   (lubrication). Such materials  include polymeric   compo-
sites.
       Technological  progress was  based  exclusively on the use of natural materials –
wood,  stone, metals, by the beginning  of the twentieth century.
       The  human   used natural polymers   for many   years: cellulose, rubber, leather.
Synthetic polymers   were first obtained in the first half of the twentieth century, this is
the beginning  of the century of synthetic polymer  materials.
       Now  a special place  in the modernization  of machines   belongs  to plastics, in-
creasing their reliability, reducing metal consumption.  The  unique  properties of plas-
tics improve designs, improve  their quality, reduce cost, increase labor productivity [3,
4].
       Plastics used in engineering are divided into five groups: decorative, structural,
antifriction, anticorrosive, electrical insulating.
       To improve  the technical level of machines and agricultural machinery  use struc-
tural and antifriction plastics. For this purpose: polyamides, capron, polyethylene with
various dispersed  and fibrous fillers are often used.
       Today,  the use of complex   plastics with different modifiers and  fillers form a
new  group  of high-tech materials – polymer  composite  materials. Application of poly-
meric composite   materials in engineering and agriculture occupies  an important  place.
This also applies to soil-cultivating machinery,  which  is improved  for agronomic   re-
quirements  [4].
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
