<SECTION_HEADER>
Beyond the VIX Index
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
In addition to the VIX Index, Cboe calculates several other broad market volatility indexes including the Cboe Short- Term Volatility Index (VIX9DSM), which reflects 9-day expected volatility of the S&P 500 Index, the Cboe S&P 500® 3-Month Volatility Index (VIX3MSM), Cboe S&P 500® 6-Month Volatility Index (VIX6MSM) and the Cboe S&P 500 1-Year Volatility Index (VIX1YSM). Cboe also calculates the Nasdaq-100® Volatility Index (VXNSM), Cboe DJIA® Volatility Index (VXDSM) and the Cboe Russell 2000® Volatility Index (RVXSM).
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Historical Prices: The VIX Index and Other Volatility Indexes
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Perhaps one of the most valuable features of the VIX Index is the existence of more than 25 years of historical prices. This extensive data set provides investors with a useful perspective of how option prices have behaved in response to a variety of market conditions. Price history for the original Cboe Volatility Index (VXO) based on OEX options is available from 1986 to the present. Cboe has created a similar historical record for the new VIX Index dating back to 1990 so that investors can compare the new VIX Index with VXO, which reflects information about the volatility “skew” or “smile.”
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
The VIX Index Calculation: Step-by-Step
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
The VIX Index is a volatility index comprised of options rather than stocks, with the price of each option reflecting the market’s expectation of future volatility. Like conventional indexes, the VIX Index calculation employs rules for selecting component options and a formula to calculate index values. Some different rules and procedures apply when calculating the VIX Index value to be used for the final settlement value of VIX futures and options. For more information about those differences, refer to the section below titled “The Calculation of the Final Settlement Value for VIX Derivatives.”
</TEXT>
<FORM>
2
2       2                      RT                          1
  =                     2 i e       Q  ( K  i )                   KF        1
        T     i     KK                                     T         0
                        i
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Where
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
VIX                                                               K         Interval between   strike prices – half the
             100                                                          i      difference between   the  strike on either side of K i:
T    Time  to expiration                                                                        1      K   i 1
                                                                                  K   =   K  i +
F    Forward   index  level derived from  index  option  prices                     i              2
K  0 First strike below the  forward  index  level, F
                                                                     R           Risk-free interest rate to expiration
K  i Strike price of ith out-of-the-money   option; a call if
                                                                 R   Q  (K  i )  The midpoint   of the bid-ask  spread  for each
     K i > K 0 and a put if K i< K 0; both put and call if K i=K 0.              option with  strike K i.
</FORM>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
Page 4
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
The  generalized    formula   used   in the VIX  Index  calculation§   is:
                                         Cboe Proprietary Information. Copyright © 2019 Cboe. All rights reserved.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
