<FORM>
2018                          California                       e-fle             Signature                        Authorization                                 for       Individuals                                               8879
Your   name                                                                                                                                                                                          Your   SSN     or  ITIN
Spouse’s/RDP’s          name                                                                                                                                                                        Spouse’s/RDP’s           SSN    or  ITIN
Part       I    Tax    Return     Information         (whole      dollars     only)
1     California      Adjusted      Gross      Income.      See    instructions        . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 1
2     Amount       You    Owe.     See    instructions         . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 2
3     Refund      or  No    Amount       Due.    See    instructions         . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 3
Part       II     Taxpayer       Declaration         and    Signature        Authorization         (Be    sure    you   obtain     and    keep    a  copy     of  your    return.)
</FORM>
<TEXT>
Under penalties of perjury, I declare that I have examined a copy of my individual income tax return and accompanying schedules and statements for the tax year ending December 31, 2018, and to the best of my knowledge and belief, it is true, correct, and complete. I further declare that the information I provided to my electronic return originator (ERO), transmitter, or intermediate service provider (including my name, address, and social security number or individual tax identifcation number) and the amounts shown in Part I above agree with the information and amounts shown on the corresponding lines of my electronic income tax return. If applicable, I authorize an electronic funds withdrawal of the amount on line 2 and/or the estimated tax payments as shown on my return and on form FTB 8455, California e-fle Payment Record for Individuals, or a comparable form. If applicable, I declare that direct deposit refund amount on line 3 agrees with the direct deposit authorization stated on my return. If I have fled a joint return, this is an irrevocable appointment of the other spouse/RDP as an agent to authorize an electronic funds withdrawal or direct deposit. I authorize my ERO, transmitter, or intermediate service provider to transmit my complete return to the Franchise Tax Board (FTB). If the processing of my return or refund is delayed, I authorize the FTB to disclose to my ERO, intermediate service provider, and/or transmitter the reason(s) for the delay or the date when the refund was sent. If I am fling a balance due return, I understand that if the FTB does not receive full and timely payment of my tax liability, I remain liable for the tax liability and all applicable interest and penalties. I acknowledge that I have read and consent to the Electronic Funds Withdrawal Consent included on the copy of my electronic income tax return. I have selected a personal identifcation number (PIN) as my signature for my electronic income tax return and, if applicable, my Electronic Funds Withdrawal Consent.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Taxpayer’s PIN: check one box only
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
I will enter my PIN as my signature on my 2018 e-fled California individual income tax return. Check this box only if you are entering your own PIN and your return is fled using the Practitioner PIN method. The ERO must complete Part III below. □
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Spouse’s/RDP’s PIN: check one box only
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
I certify that the above numeric entry is my PIN, which is my signature for the 2018 California individual income tax return for the taxpayer(s) indicated above. I confrm that I am submitting this return in accordance with the requirements of the Practitioner PIN method and FTB Pub. 1345, 2018 Handbook for Authorized e-fle Providers.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
FTB 8879 2018
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<PAGE_HEADER>
DO NOT MAIL THIS FORM TO THE FTB
</PAGE_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
TAXABLE    YEAR                                                                                                                                     FORM
□    I authorize                                                                                                    to enter my PIN
                                                        ERO  frm  name                                                                 Do not enter all zeros
     as my  signature on my  2018 e-fled California individual income tax return.
Your signature                                                                                   Date 
□    I authorize                                                                                                    to enter my PIN
                                                        ERO  frm  name                                                                 Do not enter all zeros
     as my  signature on my  2018 e-fled California individual income tax return.
□    I will enter my PIN  as my  signature on  my  2018  e-fled California individual income tax return. Check this box only  if you are entering your own  PIN
     and  your return is fled using the Practitioner PIN method. The ERO must complete  Part III below.
Spouse’s/RDP’s  signature                                                                                  Date  
Part   III  Certifcation and Authentication  —  Practitioner PIN Method  Only
ERO’s  EFIN/PIN. Enter your six-digit EFIN followed by your fve-digit self-selected PIN.
                                                                                                         Do  not enter all zeros
ERO’s signature                                                                                  Date 
For Privacy  Notice,  get FTB  1131  ENG/SP.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
