<SECTION_HEADER>
Property Tax Deferral for Senior Citizens
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Important: Participation in this program is voluntary. If you participate, a tax lien will be placed on your property. This lien must be satisfied when your property is sold. In the event of your death, your heirs must satisfy the lien before they can acquire clear title. Read the instructions on the back carefully before completing this application.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
Your name                                                   Social Security number            Date of birth
Spouse’s  name                                              Social Security number            Date of birth
Mailing address
City                                                        State         Zip code            County
Last year’s total household income      Parcel ID number  from  tax statement   Year  property was purchased
$
Estimated  market  value (from Notice   Is property currently classified        Year  homestead   was established
of Real Estate Value or tax statement)  as homestead?
$                                            Yes       No
Legal description of property (or you can attach a copy of your deed)
</FORM>
<FORM>
here  Applicant’s signature                                                Date                   Daytime  phone
Sign  Spouse’s  signature                                                  Date                   Daytime  phone
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
You must attach the following to this application:
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
• For “Torrens” property, the report is a copy of the original certificate of title, which is available from your county recorder (sometimes referred to as a “condition of register”). The certificate must be dated within 30 days of your application. • For abstract property, the report is prepared by a licensed abstracter showing the last deed recorded and any unsatisfied liens or judgments (sometimes referred to as an “owners and encumbrances report”). The report must be dated within 30 days of your application.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
(Rev. 11/13)
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                                                                                                      CR-SCD
type
or
Print
Income/Property
       1. A copy of this year’s property tax statement.
       If you don’t know what kind of property you have, contact  your county recorder.
       Mail your completed   application  with the attachments   listed above  to:
       Minnesota  Revenue
       Mail Station 4108
       St. Paul, MN 55146-4108
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
