<TITLE>
Reduced Course Load: F-1/J-1 Students
</TITLE>
<FORM>
Last Name:                                                         First Name:
IIT ID#:                                                           SEVIS ID#:
IIT Email:                                                         Phone  #:
Degree  Level:                                                     Major:
</FORM>
<TEXT>
 Completion of Program: This option may be used only one time. The student is graduating during the current term and needs only ________ credits to complete the degree requirements. The last course MUST be on campus (not online or at another university). You will receive a new I-20/DS-2019 with a shortened program end date prior to graduation.  Graduate Students Taking Qualifying/Comprehensive Exam: This option may be used only one time. The student is taking the qualifying/comprehensive exam this semester/quarter and will be registered for 6 credits. The student must enroll full- time during all subsequent semesters of coursework, even if the exams need to be repeated.  Graduate students working on a degree REQUIRED project: The student is either completing all coursework this term and is also working on a REQUIRED project or has already completed all coursework and is only working on a REQUIRED project. The student must be enrolled in at least one special problems credit hour (594 or 597) each term until completion of the program.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Medical Condition: Cannot accumulate more than 12 months of Reduced Course Load exemption for this reason per academic program. The student has shown a letter from a licensed US medical doctor/clinical psychologist that he/she should take a reduced course load/refrain from taking courses during the current term. Please attach the letter to this form.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
STUDENT & ADVISOR ACKNOWLEDGEMENT (TO BE COMPLETED BY THE STUDENT & ADVISOR)
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
 Impending failure of a course, financial hardship, or intent to delay graduation are NOT acceptable reasons to take a reduced course load.  Students working on a thesis/dissertation and enrolled in 591/691 or LAW 895 are considered to be enrolled full-time do not require this form.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
This will apply for               (semester)               (year)
Student  Signature:                                                                      Date:
Advisor  Signature:                                                                      Date:
Advisor  Name   (Printed):                                                      Phone   Extension:
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
International Center
</SECTION_HEADER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
REASON    FOR  REDUCED    COURSE    LOAD   (TO BE COMPLETED BY THE ADVISOR – SELECT ONLY ONE  REASON)
                                                                        (Graduate); 6 credits (Grad TA/RA)
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
