<TABLE>
5 to 20 Nautical Miles             20 to 50 Nautical Miles
                     < 30 m    => 30 m       %                                   %
      Region          deep      deep      Exclusion      < 30 m    => 30 m   Exclusion
New  England          9,900     41,600       67           2,700   166,300       33
Mid-Atlantic States  46,500      8,500       67          35,500   170,000       33
California            2,650     57,250       67               0   238,300       33
Pacific Northwest      725      34,075       67               0     93,700      33
  Total              59,775   141,425        67          38,200   668,300       33
</TABLE>
<SECTION_HEADER>
RESOURCE UTILIZATION TECHNOLOGIES
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Wind turbines will be used to harness the kinetic energy of the moving air over the oceans on the OCS and convert it to electricity. Offshore winds are less turbulent (because the ocean is flat relative to onshore topography), and they tend to flow at higher speeds than onshore winds, thus allowing turbines to produce more electricity. Because the potential energy produced from the wind is directly proportional to the cube of the wind speed, increased wind speeds of only a few miles per hour can produce a significantly larger amount of electricity. For instance, a turbine at a site with an average wind speed of 16 mph would produce 50% more electricity than at a site with the same turbine and average wind speeds of 14 mph (Offshore Wind 2006).
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Historical Perspective
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
As early as 200 B.C., wind was reportedly used to pump water in China and grind grain in the Middle East. Over the centuries, onshore wind has been harnessed to generate power worldwide. In the nineteenth century, settlers in the United States used windmills to generate electricity for homes and pump water for consumption and crop irrigation; industrialization sparked the development of larger windmills to generate electricity for commercial purposes. Interest in wind energy has waxed and waned with the price of fossil fuels. After the 1973 Arab oil embargo, new ways of converting wind energy into useful power were developed. Many of these approaches have been demonstrated in wind facilities (also known as wind farms, wind power plants, or wind projects), which are groups of turbines that feed electricity into the utility grid. Wind facilities began appearing in California in the 1980s, and, today, the cost of onshore wind-generated electricity is close to that generated from conventional utilities in some locations.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
Wind energy is the fastest growing energy source worldwide at about 20 to 30% per year. The worldwide installed capacity of onshore grid-connected wind power is about 40 GW. Turbine sizes have increased over the past two decades. In the mid-1980s, the rotor (blades and hub) diameter was about 20 m; today, rotor diameters are 100 m or more (bigger than the wingspan of a 747 aircraft), with the rotating blades covering an area the size of a football field.
</TEXT>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
3
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
TABLE    1  Offshore  Resource  Estimates   (MW)
Source: Musial and Butterfield (2004).
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
