<TITLE>
Language Program Exit (Reclassification) Criteria (20 U.S.C. Section 6312[e][3][A][vi])
</TITLE>
<FORM>
Required   Criteria   (California Education               Alvord   Unified  School  District Reclassification  Criteria
           Code   Section 313[f])
English Language  Proficiency Assessment       A  score of 4 Overall on the ELPAC Summative.
Teacher Evaluation                             A  grade of 3/C- or higher in English Language Arts for most recent completed semester,
                                               or Teacher Evaluation Tool if student met English Language and Basic Skills
                                               assessment  criteria but did not meet the ELA grade criteria.
Parental Opinion and Consultation              Parent Notice and Participation
Comparison  of Performance  in Basic Skills    A  minimum   basic skills score* on an English Language Arts assessment:
                                               (PELI/DIBELS,    CAASPP   ELA,  PSAT).   *varies by grade & test
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Description of Program Options and Goals for EL
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Structured English Immersion (SEI) Program: A language acquisition program for English learners at the beginning levels of English language proficiency in which classroom instruction is provided in English, but with curriculum and a presentation designed for pupils who are learning English. At minimum, students are offered ELD and access to grade level academic subject matter content. Some assistance may be provided in the primary language when available. English Language Mainstream (ELM): A language acquisition program for English learners at the intermediate or higher levels of English language proficiency. At minimum, students are offered ELD and access to grade level academic subject matter content. Students receive any additional support needed to recoup academic deficits that may have been incurred while learning English as a second language and be reclassified as fluent English proficient. Dual-Language Immersion (DLI) Program: Also referred to as Two-Way Immersion. A language acquisition program that provides language learning and academic instruction for native speakers of English and native speakers of Spanish, with the goals of high academic achievement, first and second language proficiency, and cross-cultural understanding. This program begins in kindergarten (K) and is offered at Terrace and Valley View elementary schools.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
student to which all of the following apply: (1) is enrolled in grades six through twelve, inclusive; and (2) has been enrolled in a U.S. school for six or more years; and (3) has remained at the same English language proficiency level for two or more consecutive prior years, or has regressed to a lower English language proficiency level, as determined by the English language development test; and (4)For students in grades six through nine, inclusive, has scored at the “Standard Not Met” level on the prior year administration of the CAASPP ELA. An English learner (EL) student (1) is enrolled in grades 3-12, (2) has been enrolled in a (3) has scored at the intermediate English language development (4) For students in grades or fifth year at the “Standard administration of the All English learners continue to receive English language development and content instruction level of English proficiency and support any language needs they may have for full participation Additionally, LTELs are monitored for specific language needs and may be candidates Development (AALD) course offered at middle and high school settings. This course is designed career ready by specifically targeting their unique linguistic and academic needs. Please counselor regarding this course option and other available supports (i.e. counseling and core
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Requesting a Language Acquisition Program
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Parents/guardians may choose a language acquisition program that best suits their child. Schools in which the parents or legal guardians of 30 pupils or more per school or the parents or legal guardians of 20 pupils or more in any grade request a language acquisition program that is designed to provide language instruction shall be required to offer such a program to the extent possible. (20 U.S.C. Section 6312[e][3][A][viii][III]); EC Section 310[a]) We are required to provide a Structured English Immersion (SEI) program option. If you choose this option, your child will be placed in a classroom that uses mostly English for instruction. Parents/guardians may provide input regarding language acquisition programs during the development of the Local Control Accountability Plan. (EC Section 52062) If interested in a different program from those listed above, please contact the English Learner Support Services Department at (951) 509-5094 to ask about the process. Parents of English learners have a right to decline or opt their children out of the school district’s language acquisition program or opt out of particular English learner service(s) within a language acquisition program. (20 U.S.C Section 6312[e][3][A][viii]) However, school districts remain obligated to provide the student meaningful instruction until the student exits the program, inform the parent when progress is not made, and offer the parent programs and services to consider at that time. (5 California Code of Regulations a, Section 11302)
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                                                                                                              Page    2 of 2
                                       Definition  of Long   Term    English   Learner   (LTEL)/
                   At  Risk  of Becoming     a Long   Term   English   Learner    (ARLTEL)      Education  Code  313.1
Long  Term   English  Learner   (LTEL)   An  English  learner (EL)   At  Risk of Becoming   a Long   Term  English  Learner   (ARLTEL)
                                                                                                      to which  all of the following apply:
                                                                                                    inclusive; and
                                                                                                U.S. school for four or five years; and
                                                                                                        level or below on  the prior year's
                                                                                                         test; and
                                                                                                3 to 9, inclusive, has scored in the fourth
                                                                                                        Not Met”   level on the prior year
                                                                                               CAASPP    ELA.
                                                                                                  designed to provide both  access at their
                                                                                                            in all their content  courses.
                                                                                                for the  Advanced   Academic    Language
                                                                                                    to ensure that LTELs   are college and
                                                                                                see your  child’s school administrator  or
                                                                                               subject intervention).
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
