<FORM>
TABLE      4
                                               Typical    Fire  Ratings    of  Cavity   Walls
                                 Wall   Ansombly                                                               Fire  Ratings,   Houre
1d  im, (240 mm)   brick cavity  wall (sotid brick), 3 in (50  mm}   air space,                                            2
walls filed  solid af combustiole   framing   membors
Sin.  (200  min}  beick cawity wall (ectid belek), 2 in, (50 mmm)  air apace                                               3
10m,   (250  mm)   brick: easily weil ie     Sricke), 2 in (80 mm}   air space:
                   mamtiars                                                                                                4
ng  combustible               frames
9 in  (280  mmm)  solid brick and  concrete   binck,  1 in (38 mm)   air  space,
                                                                                                                           4
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Sound Transmission
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Resistance to transmission of sound in masonry construction is accomplished in two ways: the use of heavy massive walls or the use of discontinuous construction. The cavity wall employs both techniques, i.e., the massiveness of the two masonry wythes plus the partial discontinuity of the cavity.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
In cavity wall construction, the air space provides a partial isolation of the two wythes. Sound on one side of a cavity wall causes vibration of a wythe. Because of the separation and cushioning effect of the air space and the massiveness of the masonry, the vibration is dampened and greatly reduced. A 10-in. (250 mm) brick cavity wall with brick backing has a Sound Transmission Class (STC) rating of 50, which is usually sufficient for substantially reducing typical outside noises entering the building through the wall. For more information on sound transmission, see Technical Notes 5A.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
DESIGN OF CAVITY WALLS
</SECTION_HEADER>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Structural Design
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
There are many various design procedures for cavity walls. Both rational and empirical design methods are used. Rational design methods currently use working stress analysis. Limit states or strength design methods are now being written. Other methods such as a modified yield line approach, fracture line approach and elastic performance of cracked panels have been proposed for the design of unreinforced walls. However, insufficient data and lack of recognition by model building codes relegate these methods to use as special systems for design.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
The structural design of cavity walls should follow either rational or empirical methods. The rational design method is based on the properties of the wall materials and engineering analysis. This method may be used for any structure where high loads are likely or where tall walls are a necessity. The empirical method is generally satisfactory for one and two-story buildings consisting of light construction with limited floor spans and wall heights; and for multistory buildings where unsupported wall heights are not excessive.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Rational Design
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
The design of cavity walls is governed by model building codes. Most of these reference the ACI 530/ASCE 5/TMS 402 Building Code Requirements for Masonry Structures, also known as the Masonry Standards Joint Committee (MSJC) Code [2]. The Uniform Building Code incorporates similar design requirements for cavity walls [9]. Seismic design requirements are also stipulated in these building codes based on site location. A detailed design of cavity walls is not covered in this Technical Notes. For design aids and examples of design procedures, several books listed in the REFERENCES section should be consulted [5, 7].
</TEXT>
<PAGE_BREAK>
