<TABLE>
# Split   Polarity         Feature               Source
55          0.17            people         press release
54          0.30            years               abstract
50          0.13           evidence        press release
39          0.34            Nature               journal
38          0.52             zika                   title
33          0.14            planet         press release
33          0.40      American  Medical        publisher
                         Association
33          0.09           humans          press release
31          -0.01          patients             abstract
30          -0.22          protein         press release
30          0.33              95                abstract
29          -0.03          patients        press release
28          0.23       published today     press release
27          0.12            study          press release
27          0.13            years          press release
26          0.19           percent         press release
25          0.29         consumption       press release
25          0.36            foods          press release
24          0.13            fossil         press release
23          -0.25          proteins        press release
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
We find 8,436 matched pairs. We train logistic regres- sion with the same train-test split (days 1-277, days 278- 365). Using all features, logistic regression achieves an F1 of 0.6037. Although many of the positive feature are sensi- ble and similar to those found in the ranking experiments and previous research (Wallace, Paul, and Elhadad 2015; Zhang et al. 2016), we find that the negative features are dominated by alzheimers and dementia related terms in the title and abstract. These results are indicative of an oddity in the dataset provided by Altmetric, specifically the web- site Alzforum. Alzforum is an information resource web- site for alzheimers researchers and is one of the websites included in Altmetric’s news crawl. Most of the Alzforum articles tracked by Altmetric post only article metadata, and the website was marked as a non-news source due to its super high rate of publication. Before sampling, Alzforum covers 8,347 of the 34,329 scientific articles with no real coverage and is the highest frequency outlet on that subset. However, it covers only 667 of the 57,668 scientific articles with real coverage. Of 8,436 matched pairs, Alzforum cov- ers 1,380 negative and 224 positive samples. Although we control for subjects, they are typically more general, such as “neuroscience,” “psychology and cognitive sciences,” and “geriatrics and gerontology.” Thus, we are unable to control for specific topics, such as alzheimers, and logistic regres- sion learns that most alzheimers articles are unpopular.
</TEXT>
<TABLE>
Weight               Feature                     Source
0.8226                  fish               press release
0.8236                  fat                press release
0.8307               screening                  abstract
0.8803               quantum               press release
0.9044               detection                      title
0.9616           Project HOPE    -             publisher
              The  People-to-People
             Health  Foundation,  Inc.
0.9646                 early                        title
1.0459     American   Chemical  Society        publisher
1.1415                 time                         title
1.2791       Oxford  University  Press         publisher
-1.1910               protein                       title
-1.0599               protein              press release
-0.9404              medicine                       title
-0.9334                 cell                        title
-0.9287             mechanism                       title
-0.8788             expression                      title
-0.8500             expression                  abstract
-0.8041                genes               press release
-0.8025              following                      title
-0.7689               domain                        title
</TABLE>
<SECTION_HEADER>
5.5 Condition on Press Release Issuance
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
Similar to the ranking experiments, we repeat the matched sample experiment on the subset of articles which received a press release. We find 3,398 matched pairs and confirm that the positive and negative instances do not have dispro- portionate skew towards any one outlet. Using all features, logistic regression achieves an F1 of 0.5794. Table 7 lists the top features for these results. Top negative features ap- pear to be those related to more technical scientific work, such as “proteins” and “genes” “expression”, while positive features are related to health, such as “fat,” “screening,” and “Project HOPE,” a publisher of health policy articles. Sur- prisingly, the American Chemical Society is a positive fea- ture and “medicine” is a negative feature when occurring in the title.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
6 Discussion
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
In this paper we present an analysis of news coverage of sci- entific articles across various disciplines, universities, jour- nals, and news outlets. After filtering out press release and abstractissuanceandcopierwebsites,weapproachtheprob- lem as a ranking one. For a given period of time, we learn to rank scientific articles by the amount of news coverage they receive. We find that textual features significantly im- prove the accuracy of the prediction over metadata features, with abstract and press release features providing the largest boost in accuracy. We find the most important feature to be whether the scientific article has a press release published
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
Table 6: Conditioned   on press release publication  on Eu-
rekAlert! or Science Daily. Daily popularity prediction. Fea-
tures: All Features. 20 most important features.
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
