<TITLE>
CONSULATE GENERAL OF BOLIVIA LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA 3701 Wilshire Blvd., Suite 1065, Los Angeles, CA 90010 TEL: (213)388-0475 / 0957 Fax: (213)384-6272
</TITLE>
<TITLE>
CREDIT CARD AUTHORIZATION FORM
</TITLE>
<TEXT>
This form authorizes the CONSULATE GENERAL OF BOLIVIA in Los Angeles, California to deduct the payment indicated below from the credit card provided by the cardholder. This is strictly a one-time payment permission and does not provide authorization for any additional unrelated debits or credits to the account.
</TEXT>
<FORM>
I                                                       authorize The  Consulate General  of Bolivia in Los
                       Full name
Angeles, California to charge my  credit card for $               US  dollars which is required as payment
for:
                                                       Amount
      Visa Application           Legalization             Other
SIGNATURE                                                                       DATE
</FORM>
<TEXT>
I authorize the above diplomatic mission to charge the credit card indicated in this form according the terms outlined. I will not dispute the payment with my credit card company as long as the transaction corresponds to the purposed indicated in this Form.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
NOTE: For your and our protection once the payment is charged this part will be detached and destroyed.
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
Account   Type:            VISA                MasterCard                  Discovery               American    Express
Cardholder    Name:
Card  Number:
Expiration   Date:
CVV2   (last three digits in the signature area for VISA/MC or Discovery; four digits on front the card for AMEX):
Billing Address:                                                         City/State/ZIP
Phone   number:                                          Email
</FORM>
<UNSPECIFIED>
                                                           Signature Consular Staff
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
CREDIT CARD  INFORMATION
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
