<TEXT>
medically related text and metadata features, such as “pa- tients,” “alzheimer,” “health information management,” and “medicine” are also important and of mostly positive polar- ity, since medical articles attract greater news coverage than, say, a recently published computer science paper. As we dis- cuss later, the presence of “alzheimer” as an important, neg- ative feature is more an artifact of the dataset than an iden- tification of trends in popularity. We also find an artifact of year (2016) of the dataset with the feature “zika virus,” due to the 2015-2016 zika epidemic in North and South Amer- ica. Three publishers appear in the top 20, the Massachusetts Medical Society, the publisher of the New England Journal ofMedicine,oneofthemostprestigiouspeer-reviewedmed- ical journals, “The Royal Society,” publisher of the less pres- tigious, but longest-running scientific journal, “Philosophi- cal Transactions of the Royal Society,” and “Elsevier,” one of the largest science publishers.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
5.2 Weekly Prediction
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
See Table 3 for results for this experiment. Relative perfor- mance on the weekly task is similar to its daily counter- part. Understandably, performance is best when optimized for and evaluated on smaller ranks for NDCG since weekly scientificarticlelistsarelongandtherearemoresuper popu- lar, possibly easier to rank, articles which can fill the top 7 or 35. Segmenting dates by week rather than day may be more realistic, since scientific articles compete for news coverage with articles published around the same time rather than just those published on the same day.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
At ranks 35 and 70, as in the daily prediction task, the models using all features perform the best, but not statisti- cally significantly better than models trained on some fea- ture subsets. At rank 7, the model trained on textual features outperforms the model with all features, but not statistically significantly. Table5givesthetopfeaturesforthemodeltrainedtoopti- mize NDCG@7 and using textual features. Again, medical and people-related terms, such as “diet,” “participants,” and “health” are quite important and of positive polarity. Inter- estingly, “protein” in the press release is of positive polar- ity on average, whereas it is negative when present in the abstract. We hypothesize that this may be because, on aver- age, very technical scientific papers, such as those mention- ing proteins and cells, are less accessible to journalists, but those which garner a press release are much more likely to be read and covered. Similar to Zhang et al. (2016) “95” (for 95% CI) is an important, positive feature, perhaps since this is commonly found in results of medical studies that may be of interest to the general public.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
5.3 Condition on Press Release Issuance
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
SincehavingapressreleaseonEurekAlert!orScienceDaily is, understandably, correlated with increased news cover- age, we repeat the same experiments on the subset of sci- entific articles with press releases posted on EurekAlert! or Science Daily. This subset consists of 20,546 scientific arti- cles. Thresholds between relevances are much higher on this subset, with thresholds at the daily level of T 1 = 3.64 and
</TEXT>
<TABLE>
# Split   Polarity       Feature            Source
103         0.60          study        press release
94          1.29      mesothelioma          abstract
86          0.18           95               abstract
75          -0.35       alzheimer           abstract
62          0.46         patients      press release
60          0.58           use         press release
45          0.24         protein       press release
44          0.21          health            abstract
41          -0.14          cell             abstract
40          0.13        evidence            abstract
39          -0.20        protein            abstract
39          0.82           diet        press release
38          0.61          years        press release
38          0.64         people        press release
38          0.20       participants         abstract
33          0.34          issue        press release
31          0.24          world             abstract
31          0.59        evidence       press release
28          0.16          body              abstract
28          0.16          years             abstract
</TABLE>
<TEXT>
level, on average. As seen in Table 3, this problem is harder, with the best performance on the daily task at 0.6065, using all features, and 0.6156 on the weekly task at rank 7, using all features. However, although harder, this problem may be more realis- tic since, as noted in the introduction, many journalists start with press materials to inform what science they cover be- fore reading original articles. Table 6 displays the top 20 fea- tures for the daily experiment using all features. Important features for these experiments are similar to those listed for the experiments including all scientific articles, except fea- tures from the press release are more prevalent. This makes sense as press releases were issued for all articles in this sub- set (and we have the text of most of them), and press releases are an important source text for journalists. We do not list features from the weekly experiments as they are quite sim- ilar.
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
5.4 Coverage vs No Coverage
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
In the previous experiments, we treat articles with news cov- erage from only automatic copying of abstracts or press re- leases as having coverage count 0. In this section, we also explore the binary prediction problem of differentiating be- tween those 0 count articles and those with any amount of real news coverage. We create a matched sampling problem using the 34,329 scientific articles with no real news cov- erage as negative examples. For each negative example, we attempt to find a positive example: 1. with the same subject fields, 2. published in the same journal, 3. published within
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
T 2 = 30.36, and  T 1 = 3.53 and  T 1 = 33.04 at the weekly
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
