<FORM>
C  ITY AND   C  OUNTY    OF  S AN   F RANCISCO                         O  FFICE  OF   THE  C ITY A  TTORNEY
                  D ENNIS J. H ERRERA                                  Direct Dial: (415) 554-4748
                                                                       Email:
                  City Attorney                                                     brittany.feitelberg@sfcityatty.or
                                                                       g
</FORM>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Via Email Only
</SECTION_HEADER>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Dear Ms. Carney:
</SECTION_HEADER>
<TEXT>
As you know, my office represents the City and County of San Francisco, including its Health Officer Dr. Aragón, who has issued a stay-safe-at-home order and related health orders to protect the residents of this City during this unprecedented COVID-19 pandemic. (See https://www.sfdph.org/dph/alerts/coronavirus-healthorders.asp.) Dr. Aragón understands and respects the importance of religion to the spiritual well-being and mental health of many, and accordingly has encouraged San Franciscans to continue to practice their religious faith in all ways that are safe. It is for this reason that the Health Officer issued a revised health order on June 11, 2020 (Order of the Health Officer No. C19-07e, the “Health Order”), which allows for in-person outdoor services conducted according to science-based safeguards that will minimize the risk of COVID-19 transmission.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
Unfortunately, and contrary to increasing medical evidence that religious services without safeguards have caused serious outbreaks in many other cities and counties throughout the country, the Archdiocese has conducted both indoor and outdoor gatherings over the past three weekends that violate the Health Order and jeopardize the health and safety of San Franciscans. These large gatherings of people indoors for a long period, in some instances reported without face coverings and with singing, place clergy, staff, volunteers and congregants alike at heightened risk of transmission of COVID-19, which can lead to serious illness and even death, and endangers the health of the Archdiocese’s parishioners and the entire community. Given the recent rise in cases and hospitalizations, Dr. Aragón’s concerns about these risks have only been heightened.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
More particularly, the City understands that Archbishop Cordileone informed all parishes and other worship sites in the Archdiocese, including San Francisco, that they could resume public Mass on Sunday, June 14, 2020. Upon learning of this direction to the parishes my office sent the Archdiocese an email on Thursday, June 11, 2020 (attached) seeking more information and making sure that the Archdiocese was aware of the San Francisco Health Officer’s determination that indoor services with congregants continue to pose a serious public health risk and are consequently prohibited under the Health Order for the time being, with a narrow exception for funerals with 12 or fewer persons and an exception for live streaming services with
</TEXT>
<UNSPECIFIED>
C ITY H ALL, R OOM 234 ∙1 D R. C ARLTON B. G OODLETT P LACE∙ S AN F RANCISCO, C ALIFORNIA 94102-4682
                   R ECEPTION: (415) 554-4700 ∙ F ACSIMILE: (415) 554-4715
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
