<TITLE>
Academic/Faculty Advisor Recommendation Form For I-20/DS-2019 Extensions
</TITLE>
<FORM>
To be completed   by student: UMID  #                                 Uniqname
Name  of Student
                     Last                                          First                Middle
Degree  Level:    Bachelor’s    Master’s     Doctoral     Other      Major Field of Study:
</FORM>
<TEXT>
Note: If you are in a joint or dual degree program, you will need to have a recommendation completed by the academic advisor from each program. If the extension is based on one of the degree programs, please provide a statement from the other program(s) confirming that it has been completed and does not require an extension.
</TEXT>
<TEXT>
 Delays caused by academic probation or suspension are not acceptable reasons for program extension [8 CFR 214.2(f)(7)(iii)].  Extension requests will not be granted solely because the student was delayed by engaging in employment such as Curricular Practical Training (F-1) or Academic Training (J-1).
</TEXT>
<SECTION_HEADER>
Estimating Completion Date
</SECTION_HEADER>
<FORM>
Required   credit hours remaining   (including DISS-CAND  995  enrollment):                                     (excluding current term enrollment)
Estimated   completion  date  :                            (term and year)
Reason   for delay (check all that apply):
       Change/add    major  field of study
       Change   in research  topics
       Unexpected    research  problems
       Student  needs  more   time due  to the following  compelling    academic    reason(s)   (please review Eligibility Criteria above for the
explanation of what constitutes acceptable academic reasons for extension):
If none of these  apply, please  contact an  International Student  and  Scholar  Advisor  at the International Center  at 734-764-9310.
As  the Academic/Faculty      Advisor   or Student   Services   staff member,   I certify that the student   is eligible to continue   his/her
</FORM>
<FORM>
Name                                            Title                                      Date
Signature                                              School or Department
Phone                                           Uniqname
</FORM>
<UNSPECIFIED>
1500  Student Activities Building  515 E. Jefferson Street  Ann Arbor MI  48109-1316
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_FOOTER>
Page 1 of 1
</PAGE_FOOTER>
<UNSPECIFIED>
     have  academic   requirements    remaining.
    PhD  students  must  comply  with Rackham’s   “Time  Limit for completing a Doctoral  Degree”  policy
     https://rackham.umich.edu/academic-policies/section4/#4-4-1
    For all Rackham   Ph.D. students,  the completion  date is the last day of the final term in which the candidate must  be enrolled for
     eight (8) hours to defend.  The Rackham    grace  period is not included in the extension.
studies  and  recommend     that the student   be allowed  additional  time  to complete   degree  requirements.
                                                                                                                                  Rev5/07 DP 11/19
                       TEL: 734.764.9310  FAX: 734.647.2181  EMAIL: icenter@umich.edu  WEB: internationalcenter.umich.edu
</UNSPECIFIED>
<PAGE_BREAK>
